<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-30T09:45:11+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DevsKrate</title><subtitle>Here at DevsKrate we inspire and endeavor to share everything about technology like Softwares, Coding, etc., and provide our best about HOW TO tutorials and BEST OF every category in accordance to our knowledge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Is PUBG a chinese game?? Let’s find out</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/why-pubg-is-not-chinese-game/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is PUBG a chinese game?? Let's find out" /><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/why-pubg-is-not-chinese-game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/why-pubg-is-not-chinese-game/">Majority of us play PUBG(Player Unknown Battle Ground) game. So we can see TENCET branding while opening the app, now lets check the fact is PUBG a china game..

+ PUBG is developed and published by PUBG Corporation, a subsidiary of South Korean video game company Bluehole. It was first developed for PC's.
+ In part of the game's success in early access, Tencent Games, the largest publisher of video games in China, approached Bluehole with an offer to publish Battlegrounds in China and purchase equity in the company.
+ Following the Chinese publication deal for the Windows version, Tencent Games and PUBG Corporation additionally announced that they were planning on releasing two mobile versions based on the game.

&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/games/pubg-release-timeline.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;PUBG Release Timeline&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;45%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/games/pubg-release-timeline.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

### Confusion check:
PUBG was banned in China in 2017(as it has violence, so their government banned). This instigated Tencent Games, the video game publishing unit of Tencent Hodings, a Chinese company to secure the rights of distribution in China. It also planned on developing a mobile version of the game, and PUBG Mobile came into existence.

Now, this is where it gets tricky. Until then, PUBG was a video game. It was Tencent Games who made a mobile version of PUBG and released it in China. This is the reason why you can see the Tencent Games logo as soon as you open the game, followed by PUBG Corporation.</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="Game" /><category term="pubg" /><summary type="html">Majority of us play PUBG(Player Unknown Battle Ground) game. So we can see TENCET branding while opening the app, now lets check the fact is PUBG a china game..</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://devskrate.github.io/assets/blog-banners/pubg-chineese.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://devskrate.github.io/assets/blog-banners/pubg-chineese.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best alternatives to Popular Chinese apps</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alternatives-to-chinese-apps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best alternatives to Popular Chinese apps" /><published>2020-06-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alternatives-to-chinese-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alternatives-to-chinese-apps/">&gt; These apps were &quot;engaged in activities which is prejudicial to sovereignty and integrity of India, defence of India, and security of state and public order&quot;

&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/banned-chinese-apps-list.jpeg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Govt Banned apps list&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;50%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/banned-chinese-apps-list.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

Here are some of the best alternatives to popular chinese apps..

### 1. Alternatives to File transfer apps:

SHAREit and Xender are the most popular file transferring apps, though they are very annoying.

**SHAREit** - It is very annoying to receive very spamy Ads and Ad notifications.

**Xender**  - The UI is clean but, it also includes many features, that deviates the app purpose and makes it spamy.

So, here are the best alternative to it is the [**Files by Google**](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.nbu.files&amp;hl=en_IN). You can easily clean the junk files and can transfer you files.

&lt;p align=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.nbu.files&amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;10%&quot; src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/filesgo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Files by Google: Clean up space on your phone&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

### 2. Alternatives to WPS office:

WPS office is an Office suite, with DOCS(Word), XLS(Excel), PDF, PPT(Power point). Previously there is no good app to provide the features bundled in one app. But now Microsoft is providing [**Microsoft Office**](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.office.officehubrow&amp;hl=en_IN) with many features like,
- Word, Excel, PowerPoint, PDF, Media, Notes in the one app.
- You can the files to your computer and a nearby device.
- You can extract text from images and also tables from images.
- You can Sign a PDF, Scan a PDF, Create PDF from pictures andConvert a document to PDF.
- Scan QR Code and save it as notes.
- Rephrase with coach, with this you can practice your presentation.

&lt;p align=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.office.officehubrow&amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;7.5%&quot; src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/microsoft-office.png&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint &amp; More&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

### 3. Alternatives to CamScanner:

CamScanner is one the popular app for scanning the documents and converting them to PDF, but there are also good alternatives for them like,
+ &lt;p align=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.office.officelens&amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;6%&quot; src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/microsoft-office-lens.png&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;bold&gt;Microsoft Office Lens - PDF Scanner: &lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It is a Microsoft App, You can also download Microsoft Office, as this feature is already included in it with out a separate app.
  &lt;/p&gt;

+ &lt;p align=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adobe.scan.android&amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;6%&quot; src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/adobe-scan.png&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;bold&gt;Adobe Scan PDF Scanner, OCR: &lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is from Adobe where you can scan your documents and it can also instantly recognize printed text and handwriting.
  &lt;/p&gt;

### 4. Alternatives to UCBrowser:

UC Browser is one of the popular app, but there are many best alternatives to this app. 
[**Chrome**](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.android.chrome&amp;hl=en_IN), [**Firefox**](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.mozilla.firefox&amp;hl=en_IN) and [**Brave**](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.brave.browser&amp;hl=en_IN) are the best alternatives to it. 
But if you are using a lite version.. Yes there are **The Best** alternatives like

{:class=&quot;table table-bordered dark&quot;}
|Browser         | App size  | Description | Image |
| -----------    | --------- | ----------- | ----- |
|[Firefox Lite](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.mozilla.rocket&amp;hl=en_IN)    | 6.1 MB    |It is a lite version of Firefox, which gives more protection to your data and privacy.| ![Firefox Lite]({{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/firefox-lite.png){:width=&quot;30%&quot;} |
|[Google Go](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.searchlite&amp;hl=en_IN)       | 7.4 MB    | A lite browser by Google| ![Google Go]({{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/google-go.png){:width=&quot;30%&quot;} |

### 5. Alternatives to Helo:

Helo is one of the popular app, but there is a local made app for it by name **ShareChat**. It is similar to Helo, made in India.

&lt;p align=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=in.mohalla.sharechat&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;6%&quot; src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/share-chat.png&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;bold&gt;ShareChat - Made in India&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Youtube and Instagram are also a way similar and can be considered as some of the alternatives

### 6. Alternatives to Turbo VPN:

Turbo VPN is one of the most used VPN service, but you got an alternative for this chinese app, it is **Hotspot Shield Free VPN**.
&lt;p align=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=hotspotshield.android.vpn&amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;6%&quot; src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/hotspot-shield-vpn.png&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;bold&gt;Hotspot Shield Free VPN Proxy &amp; Secure VPN&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="Android" /><category term="Alternatives" /><summary type="html">These apps were “engaged in activities which is prejudicial to sovereignty and integrity of India, defence of India, and security of state and public order”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/best-alternatives-to-chinese-apps.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/alternatives/chinese-apps/best-alternatives-to-chinese-apps.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Realme Buds Q with 10mm Drivers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/realme-buds-q/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Realme Buds Q with 10mm Drivers" /><published>2020-06-25T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/realme-buds-q</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/realme-buds-q/">The market for TWS in India is growing rapidly and to add for heat to the competition Realme has introduced the Realme Buds Q in India.

Realme Buds Q looks like a round pebble with rounded edges to the sides. The buds are super light, with each weighing at 3.6 grams each. The charging case is also quite pocketable and weighs 35.3 grams. Realme Buds Q comes with Bluetooth 5.0  for connectivity, but it doesn't have the support for Fast Pair.

![Realme Buds Q]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realme-buds-q-earbuds-and-case.jpg){:width=&quot;40%&quot;}

Speaking of sound quality, it comes with a 10mm Bass Boost driver, which Realme says are the largest bass driver in the segment. It also has support for super low latency mode, which reduces the latency down to 119ms. It also comes with IPX4 water resistance to prevent sweat and rain from damaging the earbuds.

![Realme Buds Q]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realme-buds-q-earbuds.jpg){:width=&quot;40%&quot;}

The buds also have touch controls baked in to control the earbuds without your phone. You can double-tap to play/ pause music, long press to call upon the voice assistant, and more. You can change the actions according to your preference from the Realme Link app. The company promises a total battery life of 20 hours of battery life, with the earbuds offering 4.5 hours of continuous playback on a single charge.


#### Pricing:
The Realme Buds Q has been priced at Rs. 1,999 in India and will be available in three colors namely Quite Black, Quite White, and Quite Yellow. It will go on sale starting from 1st July via Amazon India and Realme’s online store. You will also be able to buy them in offline stores soon. 
![Realme Buds Q]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realme-buds-q-colors.jpg)</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="Realme" /><category term="Realme Buds Q" /><category term="TWS" /><summary type="html">The market for TWS in India is growing rapidly and to add for heat to the competition Realme has introduced the Realme Buds Q in India.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/realme-buds-q-banner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/realme-buds-q-banner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Realme X3 and Realme X3 SuperZoom launched in India</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/realme-x3-and-realme-x3-superzoom-specs-and-price-in-india/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Realme X3 and Realme X3 SuperZoom launched in India" /><published>2020-06-25T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/realme-x3-and-realme-x3-superzoom-specs-and-price-in-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/realme-x3-and-realme-x3-superzoom-specs-and-price-in-india/">Realme earlier this year launched its X50 pro with Snapdragon 865 with 5G support, but in India 5G is not out yet and is expected any time soon, so they wanted to offer the best 4G phone at lower price to appeal to wider range of audience and released the Realme X3 and X3 superzoom. Realme X3 SuperZoom was first launched in Europe earlier last month while it is the first time that the company is talking about the regular Realme X3. Lets see what this phone has to offer.

#### Design and Display:
Talking about the design, it's a glass sandwich build which is held together by a plastic frame. It is protected by Gorilla Glass 5 on the front and back. This phone comes with dual punch-hole cutouts to accommodate two cameras. Speaking of display it comes with 6.6 inch 120Hz IPS LCD panel, 120 Hz is good but would have loved to see Amoled instead of the IPS LCD. Since it is an LCD panel it comes with a side-mounted fingerprint scanner.

![Realme X3 series Display and design]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realmex3-display.jpg)

#### Internals and software:
Speaking of internals, It comes with the previous year’s flagship processor from Qualcomm-Snapdragon 855 plus, which still is quite fast. It will come with the option to spec the phone up to 12 GB LPDRR4x RAM and 256 GB UFS 3.0 internal storage. It will not support 5G but it will come with Bluetooth 5.0, dual-frequency GPS, and WiFi 802.11ac for connectivity. It also comes with liquid cooling chamber to keep the temperature on check. Speaking of battery capacity, This phone will have 4200 mAh and a 30W charger for fast charging. Coming to Software, it comes with Realme UI based on Android 10 running the show.  

#### Camera:
Realme X3 superzoom comes with a Quad-Rear camera setup, The primary camera being a 64 MP, f/1.8 lens. The second sensor and the highlight of the phone is the 8MP Periscope zoom lens, which offers five times of lossless zoom and can go up to sixty times with digital zoom. The third is an 8MP ultra-wide with a 115-degree FOV and the last one is a 2MP macro lens. The regular Realme X3 replaces the periscope camera for a standard 12MP telephoto sensor with 2x optical zoom.

Looking to the Selfie camera, Both come with a dual-camera setup inside the punch hole but with different sensors, the SuperZoom comes with 32MP primary sensor and an 8MP ultra-wide sensor with a 105-degree FOV, while the regular comes with 16MP primary sensor and an 8MP ultra-wide sensor.

![Realme X3 series Camera]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realmex3-camera.jpg)

#### Pricing:
The regular Realme X3 is priced at Rs. 24,999 for the 6GB+128GB base variant whereas the higher-end 8GB+128GB variant is priced at Rs. 25,999 in India.

Realme X3 SuperZoom, on the other hand is priced at 27,999 for the 8GB+128GB base variant whereas the higher-end 12GB+256GB variant is priced at Rs. 32,999 in India.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="Realme" /><category term="Realme X3" /><category term="Realme X3 SuperZoom" /><summary type="html">Realme earlier this year launched its X50 pro with Snapdragon 865 with 5G support, but in India 5G is not out yet and is expected any time soon, so they wanted to offer the best 4G phone at lower price to appeal to wider range of audience and released the Realme X3 and X3 superzoom. Realme X3 SuperZoom was first launched in Europe earlier last month while it is the first time that the company is talking about the regular Realme X3. Lets see what this phone has to offer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/realmex3-banner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/realmex3-banner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple ios 14</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/apple-ios14-wwdc-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple ios 14" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/apple-ios14-wwdc-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple-ios14-wwdc-2020/">Apple's home screen hasn't changed much since the launch of it's first iphone.
The new operating system brings a redesigned home screen and much-needed features to catch up with what Android has to offer.

+ **App Library:**
This feature allows us to access and organize our apps much easier by creating a new space called the App library at the end of the home screen pages. It creates folders based on the type of apps and even has a separate folder for frequently used apps. It even has the option to hide pages, which you don't use.

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-app-library.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;ios14 App Library&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-app-library.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **Improved Widgets:**
Anything we miss when we switch from Android to iOS is a lack of widgets on the home screen. This feature now lets you do just that, not only that you can even resize your widgets according to your wish. This even has a widget gallery, which contains all the available widgets available for a particular app. There’s also a new “Smart Stack” widget that automatically shows relevant apps based on the time of day.

&lt;center&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-widgets.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-widgets.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **Picture - In- Picture Mode for Videos:**
Apple finally added system-wide picture-in-picture mode to iOS 14, which basically lets you hover over apps and adjust in size and you can even collapse into the side of the display to continue playing in the background.

&lt;center&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-pip.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-pip.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **Siri:**
The most annoying thing when you call for Siri is that it takes up the whole screen and Apple addresses this problem with the introduction of a new compact design, there’s just a small animated Siri icon at the bottom. Siri can now take answers from the website. Siri can now help send audio messages in addition to just dictated messages.

&lt;center&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-siri.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-siri.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **Translate App:**
Apple also introduced a new Translate app that will come built-in with iOS 14. It will allow users to easily translate between languages. Users will be able to enter text in or dictate messages and have them translated into 11 languages. English, Mandarin Chinese, French, German, Spanish, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Arabic, Portuguese, and Russian will all be supported at launch and the fact that it is available offline makes it even more useful.

&lt;center&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-translate.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-translate.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **Messages:**
Messages are also getting new features in iOS 14, now you will be able to pin important conversations to the top of the Message app to easily talk to your favorite friends or group chats. There is also 20 new hairstyle and even mask option and even ages options for memojis and there is also an option for groups inline replies, which helps to keep track of the conversations happening in the groups.

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-messages.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-messages.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-messages-1.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-messages-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **Apple Maps:**
Apple Maps is getting new, curated guides from companies like Zagat or AllTrails to give better recommendations for new places. Maps is also giving a new option for cycling, with dedicated directions for bike-riding. Cycling will launch in NYC, LA, San Fransisco’s Bay Area, Shanghai, and Beijing. There is also a new EV Routing feature, which will track the current charge of your car and route you to compatible stations.

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-maps.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-maps.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-maps-1.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-maps-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **CarPlay and Carkeys:**
CarPlay is getting support for custom wallpapers and new app categories: parking apps, EV chargers, and fast food takeout apps.CarKeys will let you leave your keys at home and use your iPhone as a key to lock/unlock your car. You can even share the hey using messages app and you can even apply a restricted driving profile. This feature will not only be an iOS 14 exclusive but will be supported iniOS 13 as well. The 2021 BMW 5 Series will be the first car to come with support for car keys.

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-keys.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-keys.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

+ **AppClips:**
AppClips will let users access a small part of the app that you need without downloading the app. The new feature is meant to help users have quick access to the app. When you scan a QR code, a dedicated App Clip code or NFC tags, your iPhone will launch the App Clip card. You can tap Open to launch the app without downloading it. App Clips are compatible with Apple Pay and Sign in with Apple. This means you don't have to make an account with an app or use your credit card information. Users will be able to pay for takeout, parking, and learn more about local businesses just by scanning.
iOS 14 will be out this fall, but a developer preview will be available to Apple Developer Program members starting today, with plans for a public beta for all iOS users in July. iOS 14 will work on the iPhone 6S and up — the same devices that supported iOS 13.

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-clips.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-clips.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-clips-1.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-clips-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

### List of devices getting the update..

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CBxU90UpYCD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CBxU90UpYCD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CBxU90UpYCD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by DevsKrate (@devskrate)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-06-23T08:22:51+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 23, 2020 at 1:22am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="ios" /><category term="iphone" /><category term="wwdc" /><summary type="html">Apple’s home screen hasn’t changed much since the launch of it’s first iphone. The new operating system brings a redesigned home screen and much-needed features to catch up with what Android has to offer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-banner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ios14-banner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple iPadOS 14 and macOS - Big Sur</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/apple-ipados14-and-macos-bigsur-wwdc-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple iPadOS 14 and macOS - Big Sur" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/apple-ipados14-and-macos-bigsur-wwdc-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple-ipados14-and-macos-bigsur-wwdc-2020/">Apple released it's new iPadOS 14 and Mac OS Big Sur

#### iPad OS:

+ iPadOS 14, the latest version of iPadOS brings everything that iOS 14 packs, with some major redesign to how the interface looks on iPad's large screens. 
Siri is also getting a makeover on the iPadOS, it's now a lesser space with only a small icon on the bottom right corner, much like the iOS. 

+ The ipadOS also borrows features like universal search from macOS, which also you to not only on your home screens but also on any app. The ipadOS also brought several features to productivity apps like photos, calendars and redesigned them to make use of the much bigger screen real-estate available.

+ With this ipadOS update, Apple focused on making the already useful Apple Pencil much more useful. Apple Pencil now gets Scribble mode, which turns your scribbling into proper texts. This text can be copied and pasted anywhere. 

+ You can use scribble mode in the search menu as well. The iPadOS is getting a compact screen window for calls.The developer beta of iPadOS 14 is available today while the stable versions will launch this fall.

&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ipados14-handwriting.gif&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;65%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ipados14-handwriting.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ipados14-ar.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ipados14-ar.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

#### macOS:

Apple named its latest macOS as Big Sur. The biggest change is the new look. This is what Apple considers the biggest redesign after the introduction of macOS 10. 

Like the ipadOS, macOS takes much of its queues from iOS, including a control center for customizing brightness, Do Not Disturb, and several other settings. It also adds a new notification center, which keeps all of your notifications and widgets. It also brings pinned messages and several other message feature to the mac's message app. Apple maps also have the same feature changes to that of iOS 14.

Big Sur also features improvements to its core applications. Safari now features a new start page with customizable background images and sections like Reading List and iCloud Tabs. It also adds Safari can now also detect when you're on a page with non-native language and offer to translate it for you similar to google translate on chrome. 

The tab UI has also been changed with increased size and preview for tabs and the ability to close all the tabs which are right of the selected tab. 

Apple also claims Safari to the faster browser. Apple has also improved extension support, which allows developers to bring in their extensions from other browsers, which can be found on the Mac App Store but they can only access your data once you allow them. Safari also shows which trackers are being blocked by the browser.

Apple also announced the Mac platform will now be transferred to ARM and apple will be making its own A-series custom chipsets and Apple promises to bring its first ARM-powered machine by the end of the year and the transition from Intel to ARM will take two years. 

&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-preview.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-preview.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-control-center.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-control-center.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-safari.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-safari.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-redesign.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/bigsur-redesign.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="ipad" /><category term="mac" /><category term="os" /><category term="wwdc" /><summary type="html">Apple released it’s new iPadOS 14 and Mac OS Big Sur</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ipados-and-macos-banner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/ipados-and-macos-banner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple Watch OS and TV OS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/apple-watchos-and-tvos-wwdc-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple Watch OS and TV OS" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/apple-watchos-and-tvos-wwdc-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple-watchos-and-tvos-wwdc-2020/">Apple has released new WatchOS and tvOS, here is a quick view of them.

### Watch OS:

&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/apple-watch-os7.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;ios14 App Library&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/apple-watch-os7.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/apple-watch-os7.gif&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;ios14 App Library&quot;&gt;&lt;img text-align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/apple-watch-os7.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

+ Apple with watchOS 7 brings the most requested features that's Sleep tracking. This feature will let you set a bedtime and wake-up alarm and will even help you in maintaining a proper sleep cycle.
+ WatchOS 7 will have a new feature called complications, which is Apple fancy term for widgets in Apple watch. Now, developers will be able to enable richer complication combinations — more than one per app on a single watch face for the first time — so users can customize more detailed watch faces themselves. 
+ Face Sharing, which lets you share watch face with others. These will be available as curated watch faces in the Apple Watch app store or shareable between individuals or as links on social media sites.
+ The new watchOS now supports cycling directions and fitness tracking for dance workouts and Apple is rebranding the existing Activity into Fitness app. 
+ In the time of current pandemic washing hands have become much more important and to help users do it correctly this watchOS comes with a hand-washing detection system, which sets a countdown to tell you how long to keep washing to match the amount of time recommended by health officials.
+ The update will release this fall for the Apple Watch Series 3 and later, meaning Apple is dropping support for the Series 1 and Series 2. You’ll need at least an iPhone 6S or later running iOS 14 to support watchOS 7. 

#### TV OS:

The TV OS 14 comes with Home app and Apple calls it the **Home View**. This brings native HomeKit integration and features like camera feeds directly to your Apple TV experience and more. 
Home View also includes the option to quickly view any camera you want.

+ TV OS also delivers support for multiple users for Apple Arcade games, this will allow users to pick up their game right where they left off. This also has support for Xbox Elite 2 and Xbox Adaptive controllers. Apple also brought audio sharing features and Picture in Picture Mode to the Apple TV.Apple tv can also play 4k video from iPhone or the iPad using AirPlay.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="watchos" /><category term="appletv" /><category term="wwdc" /><summary type="html">Apple has released new WatchOS and tvOS, here is a quick view of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/watchos-and-tvos-banner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/wwdc2020/watchos-and-tvos-banner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What Is Moodle?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-is-moodle-how-to-use-moodle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Is Moodle?" /><published>2020-06-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/what-is-moodle-how-to-use-moodle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-is-moodle-how-to-use-moodle/">Hello Geeks, you might be wondering what this Moodle is?
The word Moodle is an acronym for Modular Object-Oriented Dynamic Learning Environment. Moodle is a free and opensource online learning management system (LMS). It is suitable for all ages and all sectors. Anywhere learning takes place, Moodle can be used. It is usually used online but may also be used on an 'intranet' within your organization. Moodle is used for distance education, blended learning, flipped classroom, and e-learning projects in schools, universities, workplaces, and other sectors.


### How to use Moodle?

**Using Moodle as an Individual or for any Organization**

- You can try Moodle's standard features on the Moodle Sandbox demo site, an empty out-of-the-box site.
- You are welcome to use Moodle for Free for up to 50 users.
- If you have the technical knowledge, you can download Moodle and install it on a server online.
- A further way to try Moodle out is to download your copy and install it &quot;locally&quot;, ie, on your computer.
- To use Moodle, you only need basic web browsing skills.


### How much does it cost to download and use Moodle?

 It's FREE! FREE! FREE!

Moodle is distributed under GNU General Public License, It is and will remain free to download and use in any way you like.


### Can you use Moodle from anywhere and on any device?

Moodle works well in all standard, modern browsers, and different operating systems. If you plan to run a Moodle site, you should be aware of your audience, their typical bandwidth, and web browsers.


### Applications of Moodle

The best way to use Moodle is the way which helps students learn most efficiently. Some applications of Moodle are
- Peer assessment.
- Discussion and debate.
- Sharing files and media.
- Collaboration.
- Gamification.
- Submitting work online.
- Independent and personalised learning.
- Assessment, summative and formative.

### Moodle Conferences

A MoodleMoot is a conference for Moodle community members, held to learn about Moodle, share experiences of the learning platform, discuss research in related educational technologies and contribute ideas to future Moodle development. Held around the world, MoodleMoots are organised by universities or other large organisations using Moodle, Moodle Partners, Moodle associations or Moodle HQ.

### How to get training in Moodle?

- Get some help at [Moodle.org](https://moodle.org/) in the Community forums.
- The [Moodle HQ Youtube channel](https://www.youtube.com/user/moodlehq) offers basic tutorials for beginners and walk-throughs of the latest features.
- For teachers beginning with Moodle, Moodle HQ offers a free MOOC [Learn Moodle](https://learn.moodle.org/) which is run twice yearly.
- You can also think of doing the  [Moodle Educator Certificate](http://moodle.org/course/view.php?id=48) to improve your skills.

#### About author:
Akash rao Mallareddy - `Web Developer, StartUp Enthusiastic, Leader`              
Follow him on [Linkedin](https://www.linkedin.com/in/akash-rao-mallareddy-055520168/), [Github](https://github.com/Akashmallareddy), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/AkashMallareddy)</content><author><name>contributor</name></author><category term="opensource" /><category term="learning management system" /><category term="website" /><summary type="html">Hello Geeks, you might be wondering what this Moodle is? The word Moodle is an acronym for Modular Object-Oriented Dynamic Learning Environment. Moodle is a free and opensource online learning management system (LMS). It is suitable for all ages and all sectors. Anywhere learning takes place, Moodle can be used. It is usually used online but may also be used on an ‘intranet’ within your organization. Moodle is used for distance education, blended learning, flipped classroom, and e-learning projects in schools, universities, workplaces, and other sectors.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/moodle-banner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/moodle-banner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New products launched by Xiaomi in the last week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mi-router-headset-and-projector/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New products launched by  Xiaomi in the last week" /><published>2020-06-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mi-router-headset-and-projector</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mi-router-headset-and-projector/">Xiaomi in India is famously known for its smartphone, fitness tracker, and laptops recently but it also makes several other products in China. These are some products Xiaomi launched in China recently.

#### Xiaomi Bluetooth Headset Pro:

![Xiaomi Bluetooth Headset Pro ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mi/xiaomi-bluetooth-headset-pro.jpg)

Xiaomi has been doing well when it comes to wireless headsets and to add up in this line up the company launched a new TWS called the Xiaomi Bluetooth Headset Pro. Let's see what this has to offer.

Unlike many other TWS which come with two earbuds, this only comes with only one but you can wear it both sides since the earbud it capable of rotating 180 degrees. The headset uses a dual microphone design to reduce outside noise. It comes with a 12mm dynamic speaker for richer sound. 

![Xiaomi Bluetooth Headset Pro ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mi/xioami-headset-pro-turning.jpg)

This is powered by Qualcomm QCC3020 wireless audio SoC. This TWS headset also comes with a 100mAH battery which can provide 8 hours of talk time on a single charger. This also comes with a charging case having 600mAH battery which further extends the battery life to about 40 hours. The case is charged using a type c port and also supports quick charger. This headset also supports  Bluetooth 5.0. 

It also features support for XiaoAI voice assistant as well as Google Assistant and Apple Siri, but if it makes it way to India we probably won't see the support for XiaoAI voice assistant. finally speaking of price it is 199 Yuan which translates to almost 2200 Rupees.

#### Redmi AX5 Wi-Fi 6 Router:

![Redmi AX5 Wi-Fi 6 Router ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mi/redmi-router.jpg)

Xiaomi under its sub-brand Redmi launched a router that supports Wifi 6 for 249 Yuan which is 2700 Rupees(apx), This is one of the cheapest router to come with Wifi 6. Let's see what does it offer for that price.

Talking about the design, it comes in white color with four independent antennae to provide a better coverage area. This router also supports mesh network, which means you can connect multiple of them to cover a wider area.

Speaking of Speed, the company claims router can support speeds of up to 1775Mbps which is about 52 percent faster than Wi-Fi  5. It can also support a stable connection for up to 128 Wi-Fi-enabled devices, which comes in handy, if you have a smart home with multiple devices like Smart TV, speakers, security cameras and more.

#### Mi Laser Projector 1S 4K:

![Mi Laser Projector 1S 4K ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mi/Mi-Laser-Projector-1S-4K.jpg)

Xiaomi, also launched a projector called the Mi Laser Projector 1S 4K. The highlight of this projector has to be the fact that it can use short-focus that allows the device to cast from 80 inches and up to 150 inches from just a few centimeters away and the company claims that an 80-inch screen can be cast when the projector is placed just 5.5-inch away and for the maximum 150-inch display, the projector needs to be placed at a distance of at least 19 inches, which is of great convenience.

Under the hood, the device is powered by a T968-H processor, which comes with 2GB of RAM and 32GB of internal storage. It supports 4k resolution and is also HDR10 certified. Speaking about the brightness, it supports 2,000 ANSI Lumens, which means that users can use it even in a brighter environment without any issues.

It also has HDMI and USB 3.0  for connectivity and the company claims that the lifespan of this Projector's light source is estimated to be around 25,000 hours. The projector is priced at 12,999 yuan which roughly converts to 139391.36 Rupees.

#### Xiaomi Mi Power Bank 3:

![Mi Power Bank 3]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mi/mi-power-bank-3.jpg)

The Mi Power Bank 3 is the largest power bank released by the company till date. Let’s see what features it has got to offer. Speaking of capacity it offers 30,000 mAh capacity which is enough to charge even huge phones with 5000mAH battery six times.    

First talking about the ports it has two full-size USB-A ports, one USB-C and one MicroUSB. You can get 18W of power output from the USB-A ports and USB-C and the power bank itself can charge via both the USB-C and micro USB. The type-c port can charge the power bank at 24W, while the Micro USB is restricted at 18W.

![Mi Power Bank 3]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mi/mi-power-bank-3-ports.jpg)

This power bank even offers to low-current mode for slower charging option to charge accessories like a smartwatch or even Bluetooth earbuds-this can be accessed by tapping the power button twice. Talking about the price, In China the power bank is priced at 170 Yuan which roughly converts to 2000 Indian Rupees. This is expected to India very soon, so stay tuned for that.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="Mi" /><category term="MiBand" /><category term="Fitness Tracker" /><summary type="html">Xiaomi in India is famously known for its smartphone, fitness tracker, and laptops recently but it also makes several other products in China. These are some products Xiaomi launched in China recently.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mi/mi-products-banner-2020.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mi/mi-products-banner-2020.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple’s new Apple Phone and iphone os</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/apple-new-series-iphone-os-apple-phone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple's new Apple Phone and iphone os" /><published>2020-06-19T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/apple-new-series-iphone-os-apple-phone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple-new-series-iphone-os-apple-phone/">Some leaks say that Apple is planning two major name changes to their products.
&lt;br&gt;

+ ios    -&gt; iPhone OS
+ iPhone -&gt; Apple Phone

This leaked from 2 well known personalities and trusted sources in Twitter  @jon_prosser and @MaxWinebach.
According to them their might be the renaming of their products.

By seeing this, we may also assume apple might enter to mid-range devices.

See, assume ios is gone and became iPhone OS, but iPhone gone and Apple Phone came, but iPhone is there in the OS not as phone.

So, we may assume soon apple is going to launch a mid ranger or may be a budget phone(no Possibly ;).

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;de&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;iPhone OS.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jon Prosser (@jon_prosser) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jon_prosser/status/1273639086939611136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 18, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Dude I got a random email saying Apple would rename iOS to iPhone OS and the iPhone to Apple Phone and I didn&amp;#39;t believe it...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;wow&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Max Weinbach (@MaxWinebach) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaxWinebach/status/1273641643950948357?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 18, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Before everyone is like &amp;quot;BUT MAX SAID IT WAS APPLE PHONE&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;No I&amp;#39;m saying I got a random email claiming it would be, i don&amp;#39;t believe it but the email was there&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Max Weinbach (@MaxWinebach) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaxWinebach/status/1273643092038627328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 18, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 


&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CBmp3LzpPff/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CBmp3LzpPff/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CBmp3LzpPff/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;May be apple might bring new budget series.. 🤔😍 Follow @devskrate 🔥 for interesting stuff and tech updates.. For more information, read our article at https://DevsKrate.com/apple-new-series-iphone-os-apple-phone/ #apple #ios #applephone #iphoneos #os #iphone #mac #macos #india #secure #privacy #update #tech #mi #oppo #oneplus #windows11 #beta #google #android #app #tech #technews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/devskrate/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; DevsKrate&lt;/a&gt; (@devskrate) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-06-19T04:53:48+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 18, 2020 at 9:53pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="iphone" /><category term="ios" /><category term="apple" /><category term="apple phone" /><summary type="html">Some leaks say that Apple is planning two major name changes to their products.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/apple-name-change-banner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/apple-name-change-banner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>