<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-22T23:26:46+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DevsKrate</title><subtitle>Here at DevsKrate we inspire and endeavor to share everything about technology like Softwares, Coding, etc., and provide our best about HOW TO tutorials and BEST OF every category in accordance to our knowledge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">5 cool Linux apps</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/5-cool-linux-apps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 cool Linux apps" /><published>2020-05-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/5-cool-linux-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/5-cool-linux-apps/">&lt;p&gt;In the recent days many people are tending towards linux use. So here are some of the cool apps which you can use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. KDE Connect&lt;/strong&gt;:
KDE Connect allow all your devices to communicate with each other.
Here are some of the things that it can do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Receive your phone notifications on your desktop computer and reply to messages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Control music playing on your desktop from your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use your phone as a remote control for your desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run predefined commands on your PC from connected devices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check your phones battery level from the desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ring your phone to help finding it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share files and links between devices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Browse your phone from the desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Control the desktop’s volume from the phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is similar to controlling your phone in Windows, but with a lot more features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download it from the official site &lt;a href=&quot;https://kdeconnect.kde.org/download.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ulauncher&lt;/strong&gt;:
It is an application launcher for linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a great tool where in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can search your apps, files in your system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can set custom color themes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can add shortcuts &amp;amp; extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast directory browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;55%&quot; alt=&quot;Ulanucher&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/ulauncher-theme.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;65%&quot; alt=&quot;Ulanucher&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/ulauncher-search.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can accesses it with a shorcut key can create a shortcut for web search or your scripts or install a 3rd party extension. It is a very cool tool..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Wine&lt;/strong&gt;:
Wine is a compatibility layer capable of running Windows applications on linux systems.
Simply you can run windows applications on your linux system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the Wine &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.winehq.org/Download&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You can also download it from the software center in linux systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;MS office&quot; title=&quot;MS office&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/wine-office.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Matlab&quot; title=&quot;Matlab&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/wine-matlab.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Adobe Photoshop&quot; title=&quot;Adobe Photoshop&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/wine-photoshopcc2015.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. AutomaThemely&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Simple, set-and-forget python application for changing between desktop themes according to light and dark hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the application caption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this application we can change the desktop themes to light and dark by setting time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is there &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/C2N14/AutomaThemely&quot;&gt;Github page&lt;/a&gt;. You can download it from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/C2N14/AutomaThemely/releases&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/AutomaThemely.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Gnirehtet&lt;/strong&gt;:
Gnirehtet provides reverse tethering for your Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It allows devices to use the internet connection of the computer they are plugged on. It does not require any root access (neither on the device nor on the computer). It works on Linux,Windows and Mac OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download it from it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Genymobile/gnirehtet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="ubuntu" /><category term="os" /><category term="apps" /><summary type="html">In the recent days many people are tending towards linux use. So here are some of the cool apps which you can use.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/5-cool-linux-apps.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/5-cool-linux-apps.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Github announced the MLH Fellowship for students</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/github-mlh-fellowship-for-students/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Github announced the MLH Fellowship for students" /><published>2020-05-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/github-mlh-fellowship-for-students</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/github-mlh-fellowship-for-students/">&lt;p&gt;These days companies everywhere find themselves quickly changing how they work. With the culture shift that comes along with remote work, it’s fair to say that collaboration is already starting to be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://education.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Education&lt;/a&gt;, always helps the next generation of developers to make their best in work. Now, more than ever, students need opportunities to sustain their growth. Github together with their partners &lt;strong&gt;Major League Hacking (MLH)&lt;/strong&gt;, solving this problem with a new program—the &lt;strong&gt;MLH Fellowship&lt;/strong&gt;, Powered by &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;. This remote program matches up &lt;em&gt;pods&lt;/em&gt; of 8-10 students with &lt;strong&gt;open-source projects and mentors&lt;/strong&gt; over a period of 12 weeks. Students will receive a stipend for the program through &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/user-images.githubusercontent.com/1874003/80812907-e87bbc80-8b96-11ea-914b-8a35398996a4.jpg?ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;github-quote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just GitHub, many other tech companies will come together and fuel this ecosystem. To kick off the program, GitHub Education plans to support &lt;strong&gt;100 MLH Fellows&lt;/strong&gt; in the inaugural class of summer 2020. These are the other partners who’re joining this coalition Facebook, DEV, and the Royal Bank of Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how GitHub describes about MLH Fellowship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;githubs-vision-workforce-innovation-to-meet-student-demand&quot;&gt;GitHub’s vision: Workforce innovation to meet student demand&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprises want to stay competitive with recent graduates, and internship programs often provide that edge. Internships also serve as a credential: For future hiring managers, an internship with a top tech company is a good indication of a quality candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for students, many, many more of them apply for those coveted roles than there are positions to fill. For most students, a summer in Silicon Valley is often out of the question for those aspiring developers, maintainers, and engineering managers. In partnering with MLH, we’re looking to welcome a new global workforce that is trained in real-world workflows and collaboration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEO of MLH, Mike Swift, points to the program’s design around remote work and public projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Enabling students to spend their summer contributing to the software that runs the world is a unique     opportunity for them. They’ll work on meaningful projects with their peers under the guidance of some of the world’s most talented engineers. The remote nature of this program will democratize access to internships for countless students worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-opportunity-shape-the-future-of-work&quot;&gt;The opportunity: Shape the future of work&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this moment, companies have the opportunity to affect how we learn, collaborate, and share for decades to come. We hope to see the results of these particular efforts in as little as 12 months when this year’s group of interns graduate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s keep education moving forward. Students, we got you. - GitHub&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;read-to-level-up-your-learning&quot;&gt;Read to level-up your learning?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply to GitHub MLH Fellowship and join them  from &lt;a href=&quot;http://fellowship.mlh.io/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share your experience with GitHub Fellowship and your feedback about our article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devskrate&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/devskrate&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, or mail us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@devskrate.com&quot;&gt;support@devskrate.com&lt;/a&gt;. Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://devskrate.com&quot;&gt;#DevsKrate&lt;/a&gt; on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="fellowship" /><category term="internship" /><category term="mlh-fellowship" /><category term="github-education" /><summary type="html">These days companies everywhere find themselves quickly changing how they work. With the culture shift that comes along with remote work, it’s fair to say that collaboration is already starting to be different.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-mlh.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-mlh.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compare-dell-xps-15-and-xps-17/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15" /><published>2020-05-19T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compare-dell-xps-15-and-xps-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compare-dell-xps-15-and-xps-17/">&lt;p&gt;Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has made big changes to its XPS lineup, with the much-rumored redesign of the XPS 15 and a new XPS 17.
What do these laptops bring to the market let’s find in this article?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets first talk about the XPS 15, The new XPS 15 design has seen a significant redesign after nearly 5 years and it now comes with a bigger 16:10 aspect ratio and trimmed down bezels, similar to that of Dell XPS 13.
You can either pick a 4k or a regular FHD (1920 x 1200) display with a small webcam on top for Windows 10 Hello Facial Recognition. It also offers a fingerprint for authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-display.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Powering this is the new 10th gen mobile processors from Intel which can be equipped up to a Core i9 and it also comes with an option for dedicated graphics namely the  Nvidia’s GeForce GTX 1650 Ti Max-Q for graphically intense task.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This laptop ditches ports like USB-A and HDMI in favor of USB-C and this laptop comes with two USB-C with Thunderbolt 3 support and a regular USB-C 3.1 port, and full-size SD card reader. This laptop is quite thinner at 18mm high.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-ports.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talking about battery, Dell is promising “The longest battery life of any 15-inch laptop”, with up to 25 hours on the FHD display model and It also comes with Quad speaker setup(2 front facing and 2 at rear) for immersive sound experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This laptop starts at &lt;strong&gt;$1,299.99&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the XPS 15, Dell reintroduced it’s slightly bigger XPS 17. It’s been nearly 10 years since we have seen an XPS 17 and as the name implies it’s a larger 17-inch laptop and dell claims that “The XPS 17 is the smallest 17-inch laptop on the planet”. 
Similar to the XPS 15 this laptop also comes with a 16:10 aspect ratio and a much smaller bezel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-17.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This 17-inch laptop also comes new 10th gen intel processors, which can be equipped up to the new core i9 and at the GPU side of things, this can be equipped with either Nvidia’s GTX 1650 Ti Max-Q or the more powerful RTX 2060. With this CPU and GPU combination Dell claims this laptop to be the “Most powerful XPS laptop ever”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talking about the ports, this comes with four USB-C Thunderbolt 3 ports and a full-size SD card reader and the fact that it does not have any USB-A port is a bummer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dell has added a new thermal design to the XPS 17 with a custom vapor chamber, to improve airflow and sustain high performance for longer periods of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It also comes with Quad speaker setup(2 front facing and 2 at rear) for immersive sound experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-speakers.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Dell XPS 17 will be available soon starting at &lt;strong&gt;$1,499.99&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="dell" /><category term="computers" /><category term="versions" /><category term="comparsions" /><summary type="html">Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-2020-feature-image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-2020-feature-image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google’s FooBar - The Secret Hiring Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-foobar-challenge-invitation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google's FooBar - The Secret Hiring Challenge" /><published>2020-05-18T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-foobar-challenge-invitation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-foobar-challenge-invitation/">&lt;p&gt;Did you got Google’s Foobar Invitation. First of all, &lt;strong&gt;congratulations&lt;/strong&gt;, you should know that, this is not an ordinary invitation,, As  Google sends this hiring invitation to only some special developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you haven’t got this invitation this blog will help you to understand who are eligible and to be prepared for the next hiring challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FooBar&lt;/strong&gt; is weird term used by Google for it’s secret hiring challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-foobar&quot;&gt;What is FooBar?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://foobar.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Google Foobar&lt;/a&gt; is Google’s secret hiring challenge. Google uses this to hire some of the best developers around the globe which they think can be a good match for their organization. Many developers in Google have been hired through this hiring challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-can-i-get-the-invitation&quot;&gt;How can I get the invitation:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the invitation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://foobar.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Google Foobar&lt;/a&gt; is also a mysterious thing, no one exactly knows the criteria for the Google Foobar invitation eligibility. 
As per the known information&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google send the invitation on the basis of your &lt;strong&gt;search history&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;your problem solving related keyword searches&lt;/strong&gt;, like if you are a developer, it is obvious that you search a lot of problems related to programming on Google or Stack Overflow. And based on Google search algorithms, they show you an invitation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://foobar.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Google Foobar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the invitation looks like -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You’re speaking our language. Up for a challenge?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google/foobar-invitation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;foobar-invitation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-can-i-take-this-challenge-without-an-invitation&quot;&gt;How can I take this challenge without an invitation?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We appreciate your interest towards this but, the sad thing is without an invitation from Google, you can’t enter into this hiring challenge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we already said that Google Foobar is an invitation based hiring challenge. That means, you can only take the challenge if you have got the invitation from Google for Foobar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google/foobar-without-invitation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;foobar-without-invitation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-happens-after-getting-an-invitation&quot;&gt;What happens after getting an invitation?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get the invitation, and you accepted that, you will be redirected to &lt;a href=&quot;https://foobar.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Google’s Foobar&lt;/a&gt; website which looks like a linux command-line interface. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google/foobar-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;foobar-interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you request for the challenge using the command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;request&lt;/code&gt;, you will get some files in your Foobar command-line folder which contains some competitive programming question waiting for you.You can submit your answers either in &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;.
You will get two files to write the solution to your problem statement &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;solution.java&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;solution.py&lt;/code&gt;. You can write your solution in your preferred language out of these two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;save&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; the files and once you’re confident you can &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;submit&lt;/code&gt; and  &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;verify&lt;/code&gt; the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google/foobar-coding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;foobar-coding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar way you’ll have &lt;strong&gt;five&lt;/strong&gt; levels to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google/foobar-levels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;foobar-levels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you complete all the 5 levels, you get a form to fill your name and your contact details to contact you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you clear your interview you’ll be offered a Software Developer role at Google depending on your interests, Skills and performance in interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All the  best for your Google’s FooBar challenge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: All the images that helped you to understand better are taken from different sources like  - Google, Medium, Quora. Our  Thanks to all of the above sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share your experience with Google’s Foobar and your feedback on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devskrate&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/devskrate&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, or mail us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@devskrate.com&quot;&gt;support@devskrate.com&lt;/a&gt;. Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://devskrate.com&quot;&gt;#DevsKrate&lt;/a&gt; on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="developerstuff" /><category term="jobs" /><category term="students" /><category term="internship" /><summary type="html">Did you got Google’s Foobar Invitation. First of all, congratulations, you should know that, this is not an ordinary invitation,, As Google sends this hiring invitation to only some special developers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/google-foobar.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/google-foobar.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Microsoft Student Partner?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-is-microsoft-student-partner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Microsoft Student Partner?" /><published>2020-05-17T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/what-is-microsoft-student-partner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-is-microsoft-student-partner/">&lt;p&gt;There are many organizations that run student ambassador programs for students going through colleges and universities. One among those, but the most reputed program is offered by Microsoft named as &lt;a href=&quot;https://studentambassadors.microsoft.com/en-us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program&lt;/a&gt;, formaly Microsoft Student Partner Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/student-partner-intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-microsoft-learn-student-ambassador&quot;&gt;What is Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors program is a global group of on-campus ambassadors who are eager to help students and their communities, lead in their local tech circles, and develop technical and career skills for the future. As a Student Ambassador, you might find yourself organizing a campus or community hackathon, mentoring other students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft quoted the program as…..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Looking for student leaders with a passion for making a difference, building vibrant communities, and sharing the latest tech with their peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-did-it-all-started&quot;&gt;When did it all started?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MSP Program was initiated back in &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;, and operated in &lt;strong&gt;15 countries&lt;/strong&gt; for five years. In late &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, the program was expanded to &lt;strong&gt;50 countries&lt;/strong&gt; worldwide, and as of July 2010, there are more than &lt;strong&gt;2800 members&lt;/strong&gt; worldwide across 101 countries and regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transformation-from-student-partner-to-learn-student-ambassador&quot;&gt;Transformation from Student Partner to Learn Student Ambassador&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 1, the current Microsoft Student Partner program will evolve to become the Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors program. All active members of the program will be invited to become Student Ambassadors and the first cohort will be announced in early July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eligibility&quot;&gt;Eligibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To apply, you must be at least 16 years old, have valid identification and be actively enrolled in an accredited, higher education academic institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students from all academic backgrounds who want to grow their career and tech skills while making a difference in their communities to apply. Some experience in coding or technology is helpful, but we have tools and resources to help you learn in the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/student-partner-works.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, earning these benefits involves doing some pretty fun things. We have four milestones for our Student Ambassadors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alpha 1 - Jump on board and get active in the Teams community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alpha 2 - Complete a Microsoft Learn path and unlock Azure credits with Visual Studio Enterprise subscription benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beta - Host an event in your community to unlock event support and resource benefits. This effort could include an invitation to join our annual Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors Summit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gold - Get invited to the Gold milestone when you’ve gone above and beyond in earning your badges and serving your local community. You’ll become a Student Ambassadors Regional Leader, gain access to special events, and may be invited to become a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources-that-can-be-accessed-by-student-ambassadors&quot;&gt;Resources that can be accessed by Student Ambassadors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These benefits include but aren’t limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to Office 365, plus Snagit and Camtasia screen capture and recording software.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual Studio Enterprise subscription and $150 monthly Azure credits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Event support.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engagement with Cloud Advocates and Microsoft MVPs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Student Ambassador Milestone badges to highlight program accomplishments on your LinkedIn profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;application-process&quot;&gt;Application Process:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt;To apply to the Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://studentambassadors.microsoft.com/en-us/Form&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://studentambassadors.microsoft.com/en-us/Form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step-2:&lt;/strong&gt;Read tha Application Notification to know when does your application gets reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step-3:&lt;/strong&gt;Then fill out all your Personal Info like first name, last name, contact email, gender, and phone number, and then verify the phone number through an OTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step-:4&lt;/strong&gt;In this step fill all our College Details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step-5:&lt;/strong&gt;In this step, there are a few questions that test your view on technology and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step-7:&lt;/strong&gt;Here you have to fill all your URLs of profiles and other info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step-8:&lt;/strong&gt;In the last step, check all your Technical Skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, then submit your application for the Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program. Hope this post will help you find your path to successful Microsoft Student Ambassader Program and wish you a very good luck.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="microsoft" /><category term="student partner" /><category term="ambassador" /><summary type="html">There are many organizations that run student ambassador programs for students going through colleges and universities. One among those, but the most reputed program is offered by Microsoft named as Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program, formaly Microsoft Student Partner Program.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/msp-featured-image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/msp-featured-image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cool websites to visit, when you get bored!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/websites-to-visit-when-bored/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cool websites to visit, when you get bored!" /><published>2020-05-16T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/websites-to-visit-when-bored</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/websites-to-visit-when-bored/">Have you ever felt bored? Ofcourse YES... I know. Here are the cool websites to visit when you feel bored on internet.  
#### 1. FREESOUND  
FreeSound is the largest database of sound tracks that are available for free and when I say largest, I mean it.. So, There are tons of paid sites, that sell sound tracks. But if you ever need one, then go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://freesound.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;freesound.org&lt;/a&gt;. You can find anything for a Bleep sound to a audio of someone flushing a toilet.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/freesound.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FreeSound&quot; title=&quot;FreeSound&quot;&gt;

#### 2. NAPFLIX  
Unlike Netflix, which keep you awake at nights. &lt;a href=&quot;http://napflix.tv/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Napflix&lt;/a&gt; will help you fall asleep. It shows you hours of boring videos, which will calm you down And probably help you to sleep faster.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/napflix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NapFlix&quot; title=&quot;NapFlix&quot;&gt;

#### 3. webkay - What every Browser knows about you  
This website tells you what your browser know about you, and all the website can access these data without asking your permission. Like your approx Location, your OS and the browser, what computer are you using, what social media are you logged in and a lot of other private stuff.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/webkay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;webkay&quot; title=&quot;webkay&quot;&gt;

But what I really want to point out here is that The online sites also track your battery percentage not just in desktop, but also on mobile. So, imagine, you want to book an uber with less than 5% battery juice. Well, then then technically, it’s possible for the company to increase price just for you. Not saying this would happen, but technically it’s possible.  

Visit webkay &lt;a href=&quot;http://webkay.robinlinus.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;

#### 4. Super Log Out  
Well, talking about the browser, try out super log. It’s a simple app that automatically log you out of all the sign in account on your browser with just one click.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/superlogout.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Super Log Out&quot; title=&quot;Super Log Out&quot;&gt;

When you are using a public or friends computer though, don’t click on the link Unless you really want to use this service.  

Visit Super Log Out &lt;a href=&quot;http://superlogout.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;color:red; background-color:#D3D3D3;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;Caution: Dont Visit, unless you require it!!!&lt;/span&gt;  
#### 5. Button Bass  
This website plays a EDM loop when you tap a cube and if you are good with this, you can make your own music.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/buttonbass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Button Bass&quot; title=&quot;Button Bass&quot;&gt;

And that’s not all, There are several other genre like dubstep, electronic and yes, there are android apps for that as well. Though, there is no option to record the audio. So, you’ll have to use sound sought of workaround.   

Visit Button Bass &lt;a href=&quot;http://buttonbass.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;    


#### 6. Radio Garden  
Now, let me tell you a secret, back then in 1980, we used to have a big radio in our house. It’s quite wonderful, how quickly technology change. So, anyways, Radio garden is music website that let you listen to 8000 live radio station from all around the world. It’s a great way to discover new songs from different language.  
Visit Radio Garden &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.garden/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/radiogarden.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Radio Garden&quot; title=&quot;Radio Garden&quot;&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="internet" /><category term="bored tech" /><summary type="html">Have you ever felt bored? Ofcourse YES… I know. Here are the cool websites to visit when you feel bored on internet. 1. FREESOUND FreeSound is the largest database of sound tracks that are available for free and when I say largest, I mean it.. So, There are tons of paid sites, that sell sound tracks. But if you ever need one, then go to freesound.org. You can find anything for a Bleep sound to a audio of someone flushing a toilet.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/internet/bored-internet.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/internet/bored-internet.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">RoughViz.js - for creating sketchy/hand-drawn styled charts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/roughviz-js/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RoughViz.js - for creating sketchy/hand-drawn styled charts" /><published>2020-05-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/roughviz-js</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/roughviz-js/">Visualization through visual imagery has been an effective way to communicate both abstract and concrete ideas since the dawn of humanity. Usually we do see some cool visualizations with great look and feel. But this is an out of box JavaScript Library which helps you to plot graphs as hand-drawn charts.

##### What is RoughViz.js?
**roughViz.js** is a reusable **JavaScript** library for creating sketchy/hand-drawn styled charts in the browser, based on [D3.js v5](https://d3js.org/), [roughjs](https://roughjs.com/), and [handy](http://handyjs.org/).

See some basic examples here - 
![roughviz](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz.gif)

##### Why RoughViz.js?
Use these charts where the communication goal is to show intent or generality, and not absolute precision. Or just because they're fun and look weird. In our view those which will look weird will get more attention first than the best one. If you can create content which looks like hand-drawn images, sure you'll get appreciation.


##### Features

**Chart Types** (many more to come!)
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Bar (&lt;code&gt;roughViz.Bar&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#Bar&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/jwilber/4dc5235f7ea5e51ac1219b3605f5af6a&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Horizontal Bar (&lt;code&gt;roughViz.BarH&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#BarH&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/jwilber/419fa6d878fe6c0f79a28f9fc72d7ec6&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Donut (&lt;code&gt;roughViz.Donut&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#Donut&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/jwilber/e713c03097950d53a8cfde4c23aa292f&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Line (&lt;code&gt;roughViz.Line&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#Line&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/jwilber/ec7cbc374c2dc61b255494511e7d7ac6&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Pie (&lt;code&gt;roughViz.Pie&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#Pie&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/jwilber/d117e0b0864a161bec2d914013ed69da&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Scatter (&lt;code&gt;roughViz.Scatter&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#Scatter&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/jwilber/d02e4381d776fb9a7bcb126d3b32c85b&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Stacked Bar (&lt;code&gt;roughViz.StackedBar&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#StackedBar&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/jwilber/ee35865631cb805057142568fa5fd090&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;

Apply the features of `roughjs` to each chart:

- **roughness**
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_roughnessbars.png&quot;  alt=&quot;roughness examples&quot;&gt;

- **fillStyle**
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/rough_fillStyles.png&quot;  alt=&quot;fillStyle examples&quot;&gt;


- **fillWeight**
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_fillweight.png&quot;  alt=&quot;fillStyle examples&quot;&gt;


You'll get to know some more cool options in [API](https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz/blob/master/README.md#API) Documentation.

##### Installation

Via CDN (expose the `roughViz` global in `html`):

```html
&lt;script src=&quot;https://unpkg.com/rough-viz@1.0.6&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
```

Via `npm`:

```
npm install rough-viz
```

Want to use with `React`? [There's a wrapper!](https://github.com/Chris927/react-roughviz):

```
npm install react-roughviz
```

Want to use with `Vue`? [There's a wrapper!](https://github.com/jolo-dev/vue-roughviz):

```
npm install vue-roughviz
```

Want to use it with `Python`? 
There are two options for this.

[Option 1](https://github.com/hannansatopay/roughviz) :
```
pip install roughviz
```
[Option 2](https://github.com/charlesdong1991/py-roughviz) :
```
pip install py-roughviz
```

##### How to Contribute?

This is an open-source project by four engineers. Source is on [GitHub](https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz/)


Share your most loved extensions and your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="js" /><category term="Graphs" /><category term="JSlibraries" /><category term="Frontend" /><summary type="html">Visualization through visual imagery has been an effective way to communicate both abstract and concrete ideas since the dawn of humanity. Usually we do see some cool visualizations with great look and feel. But this is an out of box JavaScript Library which helps you to plot graphs as hand-drawn charts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/js/RoughViz.js.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/js/RoughViz.js.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">GTA V for free and more other popular games for a limited time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/todays-free-game-deals-gta-v/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GTA V for free and more other popular games for a limited time" /><published>2020-05-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/todays-free-game-deals-gta-v</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/todays-free-game-deals-gta-v/">[Epic games](https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/) is offering popular free games for a very limited time.

Check out the list.
+ [GTA V](#gta-v-game): May 14th

+ [Civilization 6](#civilization6-game): May 21st

+ [Borderlands - The Handsome Collection](#borderlands-handsome-collection-game): May 28th

+ [ARK Survival Evolved](#ark-survival-game): June 4th

{:#gta-v}
**1. The Grand Theft Auto V (GTA-V)**:
This is one the most popular game and is free for a very limited time by EpicGames. You can download it [here](https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/product/grand-theft-auto-v/home)

![GTA-V](https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/Diesel%2Fproductv2%2Fgrand-theft-auto-v%2Fhome%2FGTAV_EGS_Artwork_1920x1080_Hero-Carousel_V06-1920x1080-1503e4b1320d5652dd4f57466c8bcb79424b3fc0.jpg?h=1080&amp;resize=1&amp;w=1920)

{:#civilization6-game}
**2. Civilization 6**:
This is a Sid Meier's Civilization VI is a turn-based strategy 4X video game, it is available on May 21st.

![Civilization 6](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/3b/Civilization_VI_cover_art.jpg)

{:#borderlands-handsome-collection-game}
**3. Borderlands The Handsome Collection**:
Borderlands: The Handsome Collection is a compilation of first-person shooter video game, it will be available on May 28th.

![Borderlands: The Handsome Collection](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/d/d8/Borderlands_THC.jpg)

{:#ark-survival-game}
**4. Ark Survival Game**:
Ark: Survival Evolved (stylized as **ΛRK**) is an action-adventure survival video game, it will be available on June 4th.

![Ark: Survival Evolved](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/2b/ArkSurvivalEvolved.png/330px-ArkSurvivalEvolved.png)


**Stay tuned for the updated links**</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="Games" /><category term="EpciGames" /><category term="Free" /><summary type="html">Epic games is offering popular free games for a very limited time.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/games/epic-games-free-games.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/games/epic-games-free-games.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Github teams is free for everyone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/github-is-free-for-teams/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Github teams is free for everyone" /><published>2020-05-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/github-is-free-for-teams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/github-is-free-for-teams/">We’re happy to bring you this exciting news that Github is making private repositories with unlimited collaborators available to all GitHub accounts.
**All of the core GitHub features are now free for everyone. 🎉**

Until now, if your organization wanted to use GitHub for private development, you had to subscribe to one of our paid plans.
But every developer on earth should have access to GitHub. They told that **Price shouldn’t be a barrier.**

This means teams can now manage their work together in one place: CI/CD, project management, code review, packages, and more.
Github allows everyone to be able to ship great software on the platform developers love.

Teams who need advanced features (like code owners), enterprise features (like SAML), or personalized support can upgrade to one of our paid plans.

Github is also reducing the price of paid Team plan from **$9 per user/month to $4 per user/month**, effective immediately.
Existing customers will have their bills automatically reduced going forward.


For more information about pricing visit [here](http://github.com/pricing)

We will come up with a new mlog how to use these features for effective devlopment of your project.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="repositories" /><category term="private" /><category term="teams" /><category term="organizations" /><summary type="html">We’re happy to bring you this exciting news that Github is making private repositories with unlimited collaborators available to all GitHub accounts. All of the core GitHub features are now free for everyone. 🎉</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-teams.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-teams.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google’s Change the game design challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-game-changers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google's Change the game design challenge" /><published>2020-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-game-changers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-game-changers/">Google has recently launched &quot;Change the Game Design&quot; contest to encourage students who are passionate about game designing during this lockdown.  

Google is seeking for new and innovative ideas in designing new games and came with this challenge stating that &quot;If you’ve ever wondered what it takes to build a game of your own, tell us your idea—if you want to play it, we want to hear it&quot;. In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/google-play/change-the-game-design-challenge/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;official blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Aude Gandon, Global Brand Director of Google Play had officially made the contest live on the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Blog&lt;/a&gt;.  

Starting from this Tuesday, Google is accepting applications for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/about/changethegame/designchallenge2020/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2020 Change the Game Design Challenge&lt;/a&gt; till July 31, 2020. And with schools closed for the year and many of you spending extra time at home, they're expeceting a little huge number of applicants.  

If your game idea is selected, you’ll receive an invitation to meet other game changers. Together, you’ll participate in an online game development workshop hosted by our partner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.girlsmakegames.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Girls Make Games&lt;/a&gt;. Throughout four sessions, you’ll get a crash course and hands on experience turning your idea into a playable game.  

You can enter into the challenge by completing the form from &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/about/changethegame/designchallenge2020/enter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.

### Eligibility:  

To be eligible to enter the Challenge, an Entrant must: 
1. be a U.S. citizen or a permanent legal U.S. resident (i.e. must be able to show proof of permanent legal residence)   
2. be aged between 13 years and 18 years on the date of complete Entry Form submission   
3. have obtained a parent's or legal guardian's prior permission to enter the Challenge. Minors must have the permission of a parent or legal guardian to enter the Challenge and be eligible to receive any benefits.

### Minimum Technical Requirements:  

1. Internet Connection  
2. One of the Supported Browsers (Google Chrome 57+, Firefox 55+, Safari 11+, Microsoft Edge 16+)  
3. One of the Supported OS  
  * Windows: Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 8.1, Windows 10 or newer  
  * Mac: OS X / macOS 10.9 or newer  
  * Linux: 64-bit Ubuntu 14.04+, Debian 8+, openSUSE 13.3+, or Fedora Linux 24+  
  * Chrome OS: Any Chrome OS device updated to v57+  
  * Android: Any Android 5.0+ device with at least 1GB RAM  
  * iOS: Any iOS 11+ device</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="google" /><category term="game design" /><category term="contest" /><summary type="html">Google has recently launched “Change the Game Design” contest to encourage students who are passionate about game designing during this lockdown.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/game-changers.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/game-changers.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>