<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-13T20:27:48+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DevsKrate</title><subtitle>Here at DevsKrate we inspire and endeavor to share everything about technology like Softwares, Coding, etc., and provide our best about HOW TO tutorials and BEST OF every category in accordance to our knowledge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Google’s Change the game design challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-game-changers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google's Change the game design challenge" /><published>2020-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-game-changers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-game-changers/">Google has recently launched &quot;Change the Game Design&quot; contest to encourage students who are passionate about game designing during this lockdown.  

Google is seeking for new and innovative ideas in designing new games and came with this challenge stating that &quot;If you’ve ever wondered what it takes to build a game of your own, tell us your idea—if you want to play it, we want to hear it&quot;. In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/google-play/change-the-game-design-challenge/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;official blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Aude Gandon, Global Brand Director of Google Play had officially made the contest live on the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Blog&lt;/a&gt;.  

Starting from this Tuesday, Google is accepting applications for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/about/changethegame/designchallenge2020/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2020 Change the Game Design Challenge&lt;/a&gt; till July 31, 2020. And with schools closed for the year and many of you spending extra time at home, they're expeceting a little huge number of applicants.  

If your game idea is selected, you’ll receive an invitation to meet other game changers. Together, you’ll participate in an online game development workshop hosted by our partner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.girlsmakegames.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Girls Make Games&lt;/a&gt;. Throughout four sessions, you’ll get a crash course and hands on experience turning your idea into a playable game.  

You can enter into the challenge by completing the form from &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/about/changethegame/designchallenge2020/enter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.

### Eligibility:  

To be eligible to enter the Challenge, an Entrant must: 
1. be a U.S. citizen or a permanent legal U.S. resident (i.e. must be able to show proof of permanent legal residence)   
2. be aged between 13 years and 18 years on the date of complete Entry Form submission   
3. have obtained a parent's or legal guardian's prior permission to enter the Challenge. Minors must have the permission of a parent or legal guardian to enter the Challenge and be eligible to receive any benefits.

### Minimum Technical Requirements:  

1. Internet Connection  
2. One of the Supported Browsers (Google Chrome 57+, Firefox 55+, Safari 11+, Microsoft Edge 16+)  
3. One of the Supported OS  
  * Windows: Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 8.1, Windows 10 or newer  
  * Mac: OS X / macOS 10.9 or newer  
  * Linux: 64-bit Ubuntu 14.04+, Debian 8+, openSUSE 13.3+, or Fedora Linux 24+  
  * Chrome OS: Any Chrome OS device updated to v57+  
  * Android: Any Android 5.0+ device with at least 1GB RAM  
  * iOS: Any iOS 11+ device</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="google" /><category term="game design" /><category term="contest" /><summary type="html">Google has recently launched “Change the Game Design” contest to encourage students who are passionate about game designing during this lockdown.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/game-changers.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/game-changers.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Poco F2 Pro Launched</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/poco-f2-pro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poco F2 Pro Launched" /><published>2020-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/poco-f2-pro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/poco-f2-pro/">&lt;p&gt;Poco F2 Pro Launches as a Rebranded Redmi K30 Pro; Price Starting at €499&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poco, In February launched its new mid-ranger the Poco x2 which is a rebranded k30. As people say “History tends to repeat itself”, a somewhat similar thing has happened the Poco f2 pro is a
rebranded Redmi k30 pro.
What does the phone bring with it lets find out in this article?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Specs&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered dark&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Specifications&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Processor&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Qualcomm Snapdragon 865&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rear Camera&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Quad Cameras 64MP(Primary)+13MP(Ultra Wide)+5MP(Zoom Lens)+2MP(depth Sensor)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Front Camera&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20MP(popup)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Display&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.67 inches 60HZ AMOLED,180Hz touch sampling rate&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Connectivity&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5G, WIFI 6,Super Bluetooth&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Battery&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4700mAH(30W Fast charging)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Fingerprint&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;In-Display Fingerprint Sensor(Optical)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Charging&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Type-C cable, with Fast charging&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design and Build Quality&lt;/strong&gt;:
The massive notch of the F1 is replaced by a fullscreen bezel-less experience on the front and
has an in-display fingerprint sensor on the front as well. The rear panel has a circular camera array and Poco branding, which is beautiful to look at. Both the front and back are protected by Corning Gorilla Glass 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display&lt;/strong&gt;:
This phone now comes with a glass sandwich design put together by an aluminum frame, which is way superior compared to the polycarbonate build its predecessor(Poco F1) comes with. This phone
comes with a 6.67-inch Full-HD+ AMOLED display with a 20:9 aspect ratio. We are disappointed to see a 60Hz display in 2020 but at least it comes with 180Hz touch sampling rate and a peak brightness close to 1200nits. This display also brings with it support for HDR 10+. We can also set different color types like Enhanced, Original, P3, sRGB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/mi/poco/pocof2-pro-display.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camera&lt;/strong&gt;:
The F2 Pro comes with a quad-camera array in the circular cutout on the rear. The primary
sensor is the 64MP Sony IMX686 sensor, along with a 13MP (f/2.4) ultra-wide-angle lens with 123-
degree FOV, a 5MP telephoto macro camera and a 2MP depth sensor. The phone also supports 8k
video capture. On the selfie side of things it comes with a 20MP pop-up camera with support for slow-motion video and other cool features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/mi/poco/pocof2-pro-camera.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connectivity&lt;/strong&gt;:
This phone comes with the top of the line snapdragon 865 with support for WIFI 6,5G. This
phone also supports super Bluetooth,NFC, GPS. It also comes with a 3.5mm headphone jack at the top which is rear to see in flagships nowadays.Poco also includes an IR blaster to let you control home appliances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware and Software&lt;/strong&gt;:
This phone is powered by top of the line Qualcomm’s snapdragon 865. This also has Liquid cooling 2.0 to help the phone sustain high performance for longer periods and coming to software set if
things, It runs MIUI 11 for Poco which is based on Android 10 out of the box. The feature offered by the Poco launcher is exactly similar to MIUI 11. The only difference is that this  launcher offers a clutter-free app drawer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery &amp;amp; Charging:&lt;/strong&gt;
This phone comes with a huge 4,700 mAh battery and support for 30W fast charging, which promises to top up the entire phone in 63 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing&lt;/strong&gt;:
This phone comes in two configurations – 6GB+128GB and 8GB+256GB and has been priced starting at 499 euros (around Rs. 40,750). You will need to shell out 599 euros (around Rs. 48,900) for
the 8GB+256GB variant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinion&lt;/strong&gt;:
We think that the phone is overpriced for what it brings on board with it. If Poco really want’s this to be the true successor of the F1 it should be priced at somewhere around 30,000 rupees.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="poco" /><category term="redmi" /><category term="mi" /><category term="smartphones" /><summary type="html">Poco F2 Pro Launches as a Rebranded Redmi K30 Pro; Price Starting at €499</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mi/poco/pocof2_pro_feature.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mi/poco/pocof2_pro_feature.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI-generated memes can compete with Human-generated memes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AI-generated-memes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI-generated memes can compete with Human-generated memes" /><published>2020-05-12T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AI-generated-memes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AI-generated-memes/">I’ve spent a good chunk of my workday so far creating AI-generated memes in seconds with just simple clicks. Usually I do make memes when I'm free but after knowing that I can generate memes using AI, I started testing the algorithm and results as pretty cool. Kudos to [ImgFlip's](https://imgflip.com/ai-meme) Ai based meme generator. 


##### Why this is interesting?
At a glance, it looks like your random collection of meme templates. But those memes aren’t **real**, I mean not at all generated by humans. They are being created at that instance of time by an artificial intelligence (AI) ALgorithm that can understand meme creation technique and can generate some cool memes. You can directly ask for generating a meme with random template or else you can select a template out of 40 viral meme templates to generate a meme.

![ImgFlip]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/AI/imgFlip.jpg)

##### How it works?

These captions are generated by a deep artificial neural network. Nothing about the text generation is hardcoded, except that the maximum text length is limited for sanity. The model uses character-level prediction, so you can specify prefix text of one or more characters to influence the text generated. Using someone's name or other short text as a prefix works best.

The network was trained using public images generated by users of the [Imgflip Meme Generator](https://imgflip.com/memegenerator) for the top 48 most popular Meme Templates. Beware, no profanity filtering was done on the training data so you may encounter vulgarity.

Basically, Imgflip’s neural network processed a lot of memes and then tried to predict what memes should look like. The results are often hilarious, and they certainly feel like real memes.

Here are collection of some crazy memes generated there.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgflip.com/i/40ulhn&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgflip.com/40ulhn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

![meme1]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/AI/meme1.jpg)      
&lt;br/&gt;       
![meme2]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/AI/meme2.jpg)     
&lt;br/&gt;
![meme3]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/AI/meme3.jpg)  

Try creating different memes and share with us on [Twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate) or [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate).

Share your most loved extensions and your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="memes" /><category term="AI" /><category term="ML" /><category term="Machine Learning" /><summary type="html">I’ve spent a good chunk of my workday so far creating AI-generated memes in seconds with just simple clicks. Usually I do make memes when I’m free but after knowing that I can generate memes using AI, I started testing the algorithm and results as pretty cool. Kudos to ImgFlip’s Ai based meme generator.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/AI/AI-memes.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/AI/AI-memes.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">GitHub CodeSpaces - Your instant Dev Environment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/github-codespaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GitHub CodeSpaces - Your instant Dev Environment" /><published>2020-05-09T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/github-codespaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/github-codespaces/">Quite often we feel much irritating to shift from Dev Environment to Github and to back to Dev Environment.
**How would it be if there's a robust develop environment embedded in GitHub itself?**. Very soon Github will bring you the [Visual Studio Code](https://devskrate.com/configure-vscode-like-a-pro/) Development experience right in your GitHub within browser itself.

In order to configure your Github to make your work more productive add these extensions to your [browser](https://devskrate.com/best-extensions-for-github-part-1/).

Let's discuss why CodeSpaces will be much loved by developers..

#### What is CodeSpaces?

In a major announcement for developers, GitHub has launched CodeSpaces — a feature that lets you code directly on the web. It's like a virtual Integrated Development Environment (IDE) on the cloud.

&gt; Codespaces can be configured to load your code and dependencies, developer tools, extensions, and dotfiles. Switching between environments is simple—you can navigate away at any time, and when you switch back, your codespace is automatically reopened.

#### Why Codespaces?

As the title says Codespaces is Your instant Dev Environment. you'll get the full Visual Studio Code experience without leaving GitHub. 

Till now, to contribute to a project you would need to clone the repository, and set up the environment on your local machine according to the requirements of a project. This is the toughest part we've ever felt.
But with Codespaces, you don’t need to do this anymore. Just with a single click Github will setup the whole environment within seconds.

![github-codespaces]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/codespaces1.gif)

#### Key Features of CodeSpaces

###### 1. Code without compromise

You can code, build, test, debug, and deploy with a complete development environment in your browser. That too literally with a single click within seconds.

![github-codespaces]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/codespaces2.gif)

###### 2. Simplify your workflow

You can automatically set up dependencies and SSH keys. Go from code to commit faster on any project. This is one of the main advantage CodeSpaces will have.

###### 3. Extend and customize

As we said earlier Codespaces is your Visual Studio Code experience. you can install all the best [vscode extensions](https://devskrate.com/configure-vscode-like-a-pro/)

![github-codespaces]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-vscode.jpg)

###### 4. Develop from anywhere, anytime

Github also provides dark mode for development environment. we are sure that you'll love working there.
With your development in the cloud, you can contribute code from any device, using VS Code or your browser.

![github-codespaces]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/device-2.png)

###### 5. Dependencies, decluttered
Contribute to projects without complicating your local setup. Spin up dev environments with a click—even for projects you haven't worked on before—and switch between them with ease. Github supports all popular development programming languages support to make sure that you will have a great experience.

![github-codespaces]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/dependencies-1.png)

#### Signup for beta now.
Codespaces is available in beta. Add yourself to our early-access list to be one of the first to use it.
Codespaces will be available to a small group of GitHub users while in limited beta. Over time, more users will have access to the beta based on availability and sign up date.

[Request Early Access](https://github.com/features/codespaces/signup) for Github CodeSpaces.

Share your most loved extensions and your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="Microsoft" /><category term="vscode" /><category term="extensions" /><category term="github" /><summary type="html">Quite often we feel much irritating to shift from Dev Environment to Github and to back to Dev Environment. How would it be if there’s a robust develop environment embedded in GitHub itself?. Very soon Github will bring you the Visual Studio Code Development experience right in your GitHub within browser itself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/codespaces.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/codespaces.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Espanso - Cross-platform Text Expander written in Rust</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/espanso-text-expander/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Espanso - Cross-platform Text Expander written in Rust" /><published>2020-05-08T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/espanso-text-expander</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/espanso-text-expander/">Snippet tools are incredibly useful. The idea is to save time that would have otherwise been wasted typing phrases, sentences or entire paragraphs.

Espanso is an open source text template program for Windows, Mac and Linux that helps users save time.

During the installation, you have the choice to add Espanso to &quot;PATH&quot; (Windows System Variable) and to enable it to auto-start with Windows. You will also need to restart the computer to get the program working. properly; I think it requires the restart to enable the &quot;PATH&quot; correctly. Start the program and you should see an icon on the system tray. Right-clicking on it allows you to disable it or exit the program.

Espanso works in all applications including Notepad, Word, Firefox, Thunderbird, and more.

## Matches
Espanso uses the concept of Matches (keyword recognition) i.e., when you type a word that's present in the program's settings, it triggers the application to substitute the keyword with its configured replacement. The official wiki explains the technical details rather well, but I'll demonstrate how it works below for your convenience.

Fire up a text editor or browser, or any other program that accepts text input. Type the word :espanso and it will magically be replaced with the phrase &quot;Hi there!&quot;. In this case &quot;:espanso&quot; is the keyword and &quot;Hi There&quot; is the replaced text.

![Espanso Demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/espanso/espanso_feature.gif)

If you haven't guessed it already, Espanso is the Italian word for Expanded.


IndicateTLS highlights TLS security protocol version in Firefox's address bar 
Capture images and annotate them quickly with Draft Notes
Capture images and annotate them quickly with Draft Notes 

![Espanso Demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/espanso/espanso-highlighted.jpeg)

So, how do we customize Espanso?
Go to the application's &quot;Roaming&quot; folder in your User directory.

This folder contains a &quot;default.yml&quot; file. Open it using a text editor, e.g. Notepad works just fine. Espanso uses YAML syntax, which is very user-friendly. Look at the highlighted section in the screenshot below. That's the match trigger and replacement which I mentioned in my example.

## Rules
The indentation is necessary for the syntax to work. So if your match isn't being triggered correctly, check the spacing in the syntax. The other rule is to remember to use the : symbol. For e.g. :espanso vs espanso. The first one is correct, the latter won't trigger the program.

## How to add new words to Espanso?
Let's try adding a new one. Write a new trigger word and choose a replacement phrase. To make it easy, you can just copy the &quot;espanso&quot; trigger, paste it in a new line and edit it.
Save the document, exit Espanso and start it again. Now type :ghx and it should be replaced with gHacks.net. That's incredibly easy, isn't it? You can use it to add email signatures, URLs, HTML Tags, commonly used phrases, responses, etc, and save some time.

![Espanso Demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/espanso/espanso_yml.jpeg)

You can even replace a text with an image, the syntax is slightly different.

``` yml
- trigger: &quot;:word&quot;
image_path: &quot;/path/image.ext&quot;
```

Replace word with the keyword you want and the /path/image.ext with the full path of the image's location, followed by the name of the picture and its extension. This may not be practical in day-to-day usage, but the option is there, in case you want to use it.


**Closing Words**:
Espanso is fast, easy to use if you want to quickly insert words and phrases.</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="Espanso" /><category term="cross-platform" /><category term="linux" /><category term="mlogs" /><summary type="html">Snippet tools are incredibly useful. The idea is to save time that would have otherwise been wasted typing phrases, sentences or entire paragraphs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/espanso/espanso_feature.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/espanso/espanso_feature.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Here’s how to customize your Microsoft Teams Background</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/customize-microsoft-teams-background/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here's how to customize your Microsoft Teams Background" /><published>2020-05-07T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/customize-microsoft-teams-background</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/customize-microsoft-teams-background/">You can finally add your own background to Microsoft Teams video chats. Designed for business and education, Teams includes group chat, video calling and collaboration tools, and has seen a spike in usage since countries and states have started directing residents to stay and work from home when possible to help stop the spread of the coronavirus.

With the update to Microsoft's collaboration tool, you can now pick a custom image as your video chat background. The Zoom video chat service also lets you pick your own custom background images for calls. But with recent concerns about Zoom security, some users are starting to look to other services such as Teams for their chats.

## How to change your video chat background in Microsoft Teams

Important catch: This feature is only available for scheduled meetings, according to Microsoft. 

1. Start or or join a Teams meeting, from the Windows or Mac application (you can't change your background on the web app at this point). 

2. At the bottom of the screen, click or tap the three dots to go to your Meeting controls.

3. Select More actions &gt; Show background effects. Either select Blur to blur your background, or choose from the available images to replace it. 

4. You'll be able to preview your background to see how it looks. If you like it, hit Apply. That's it!

In the future, you'll also be able to create your own images, upload them to Teams, and then select them as a background image for your video chats, reports said.

You can have video chats with up to 250 people in Microsoft Teams, and if your workplace or school has access to Office 365, you already have access to it. You can also check out a free version of Microsoft's communication tool.</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="meetings" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="video calls" /><summary type="html">You can finally add your own background to Microsoft Teams video chats. Designed for business and education, Teams includes group chat, video calling and collaboration tools, and has seen a spike in usage since countries and states have started directing residents to stay and work from home when possible to help stop the spread of the coronavirus.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/microsoft-teams.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/microsoft-teams.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">GitTensions - Exclusive Extensions for GitHub and GitLab - part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/best-extensions-for-github-part-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GitTensions - Exclusive Extensions for GitHub and GitLab - part 1" /><published>2020-05-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/best-extensions-for-github-part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/best-extensions-for-github-part-1/">GitTesnions - This is just a funny name given to extensions exclusive to Github and GitLab to enhance your workflow and increase productivity. Trust me these gitTensions will remove all your tensions


If your answer is **YES** to any of these questions, this [mlog](https://devskrate.com/introducing-mlogs/) is for you.    
* Do you love to explore GitHub?
* Do you use GitHub extensively?
* Do you ever felt that GitHub should be redesigned to meet your needs?
* Are you a fan of [Git](https://devskrate.com/git-cheat-sheet/)?
* Are you a Developer ?

We brought you some cool and amazing browser extensions to enhance your experience with GitHub.

If you're not using any of these you're missing so much fun. What are you waiting for add them to your browser right away. you'll feel like 

&gt; **GitHub on steroids**     

#### 1. OctoTree - [Chrome](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/octotree/bkhaagjahfmjljalopjnoealnfndnagc), [Firefox](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/octotree/?src=search)

[OctoTree](https://www.octotree.io/) is a Browser extension that brings your GitHub experience to the next level. Best thing is this provides side nav-bar to browse through all files in a repo.

Features
* Easy-to-navigate code tree, just like in IDEs
* Fast file browsing with pjax
* Support private repositories

![octotree-demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/octotree-demo.gif)

There's a pro version available for this extension, explore the features of pro version [here](https://www.octotree.io/)


#### 2. Enhanced Github - [Chrome](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/enhanced-github/anlikcnbgdeidpacdbdljnabclhahhmd)
Display repo size, size of each file, download link for individual files and option to copy file contents with a single click.

![enhance-githuub-demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/enhance-github.jpg)

Features

* Displays repo size and each file size in every active branch (not applicable for folder / symlink)
* Show download link for each individual file (not applicable for folder / symlink)
* Download file while viewing it's contents and Copy file's contents directly to Clipboard.

#### 3. Git.Expandinizr- [Chrome](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/githubexpandinizr/cbehdjjcilgnejbpnjhobkiiggkedfib)

Usually we do feel irritating when Github truncates the name of file or folder, to view full name we need to open that file. But with this extension this problem will be solved.

![truncate-demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/truncate.png)

Features
 - Removes the truncating of file, directory names and notifications in the repository browser
 - Really long file and directory names will word-wrap
 - Fully expands the website, with breakpoints at 1400px, 1600px and 1800px

#### 4. File Icon for GitHub - [Chrome](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/file-icon-for-github-and/ficfmibkjjnpogdcfhfokmihanoldbfe), [Firefox](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/github-file-icon/?src=search)

On GitHub, no matter what kind of file is, their icons are all same. However, in your fancy editor, there are some packages which give every filetype an unique icon.

But this extension to replace original file icon with filetype-specific icons. This improves visual recognition on GitHub, GitLab, etc.

![fileicons-demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/file-icons.jpg)

#### 5. Isometric Contributions -[Chrome](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/isometric-contributions/mjoedlfflcchnleknnceiplgaeoegien/related), [Firefox](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/isometric-github/?src=search)

Based on GitHub contribution chart renders an isometric(3D) pixel view of GitHub contribution graphs.

This extension allows you to toggle between both the normal GitHub contribution chart and an isometric pixel art version.

Here is my github isometric contribution chart - **I'm loving it..**      
![isometric-demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/github/isometric.PNG)

##### Happy Quarantine 
Share your most loved extensions and your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="chrome" /><category term="firefox" /><category term="extensions" /><category term="github" /><category term="gitlab" /><summary type="html">GitTesnions - This is just a funny name given to extensions exclusive to Github and GitLab to enhance your workflow and increase productivity. Trust me these gitTensions will remove all your tensions</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/gittensions.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/gittensions.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Navi - An interactive commandline cheatsheet tool</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/navi-commandline-cheatsheet-tool/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navi - An interactive commandline cheatsheet tool" /><published>2020-05-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/navi-commandline-cheatsheet-tool</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/navi-commandline-cheatsheet-tool/">Do you feel command-line is only for geeks or nerds?          
Do you feel hard to remember commands and it's options?            
Here is cheatsheet tool at your fingertips which will help you to browse through commands and make note of some new commands.        
You may come across many Linux tools but this will surely help for everyone who use Linux.        

&gt; There's nothing like NewBee(Noob) and Pro in Linux. It's an ocean of resources, Usage will completely depend on the work you do.

#### What is navi?

**Navi** is an interactive cheatsheet tool written in **Rust** for the **command-line and application launchers**. Just like Bro pages, Cheat, Tldr tools, Navi also provides a list of examples for a given command, skipping all other comprehensive text parts.

**Navi** allows you to browse through cheatsheets (that you may write yourself or download from maintainers) and execute commands, prompting for argument values.

from now you will never say any of these.
- How to run that command again?
- Oh, it's not in my bash history
- Damn, it's almost what I wanted but I need to change some args

See how cool navi is - 
![navi-demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/navi/navi-demo.gif)

#### Pros of navi
- it will make you type less;
- it will spare you from knowing CLIs by heart;
- it will teach you new one-liners.
- **Open Source tool**

It can be either used as a command or as a shell widget (Ctrl-R).
![navi-demo]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/navi/navi-demo2.gif)

#### Installation

##### Using [Homebrew](http://brew.sh/) or [Linuxbrew](http://linuxbrew.sh/)

```batch
brew install navi
```

##### Using [cargo](https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo)

```batch
cargo install navi
```

##### Using install script

```batch
bash &lt;(curl -sL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/denisidoro/navi/master/scripts/install)
```

##### Building from source

```batch
git clone https://github.com/denisidoro/navi ~/.navi
cd ~/.navi
make install 
```
#### Usage

By running `navi` for the first time, you'll be suggested to download some *cheatsheets*. By running `navi` again, these *cheatsheets* will appear.

#### Shell widget

You can use **navi** as a widget to your shell. This way, your history is correctly populated and you can edit the command as you wish before executing it. To set it up, add this line to your `.bashrc`-like file:
```sh
# bash
source &lt;(navi widget bash)
```

Please refer to `navi --help` for more details or refer their [documentation](https://github.com/denisidoro/navi/blob/master/README.md)

Beauty of navi is you can see, understand and contribute to it as it is an **open source project**               
Here is the link for the repo on [GitHub](https://github.com/denisidoro/navi/)

##### Happy Quarantine 

Please share your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="dev-linux" /><category term="mlogs" /><category term="navi" /><category term="linux" /><summary type="html">Do you feel command-line is only for geeks or nerds? Do you feel hard to remember commands and it’s options? Here is cheatsheet tool at your fingertips which will help you to browse through commands and make note of some new commands. You may come across many Linux tools but this will surely help for everyone who use Linux.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/navi/navi.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/navi/navi.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Firefox containers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/firefox-containers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firefox containers" /><published>2020-05-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/firefox-containers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/firefox-containers/">Have you ever got annoyed while using multiple accounts like personal, school, work accounts in a single browser?

Yeah firefox got a solution for this,
**Firefox Multi-Account Containers**: Firefox Multi-Account Containers lets you keep parts of your online life separated into color-coded tabs that preserve your privacy. Cookies are separated by container, allowing you to use the web with multiple identities or accounts simultaneously.

+ **Open a new container tab**:
You can quickly open a new container tab by clicking on the container image or by right clicking the new tab.
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/mozilla/firefox-container-1.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

+ **Edit containers**:
You can edit your containers and can create your own containers easily.
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/mozilla/firefox-container-t.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

+ **Look and Feel**:
This is how the container tab look like when it is opened.
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/mozilla/firefox-container-3.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

+ **Sync**:
You can easily sync the containers across devices.
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/mozilla/firefox-container-sync.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

You can download the [Firefox Container](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/multi-account-containers/) add-on.

**Additional info**:
The Firefox Multi-Account Containers extension lets you carve out a separate box for each of your online lives – no more opening a different browser just to check your work email!

Under the hood, it separates website storage into tab-specific Containers. Cookies downloaded by one Container are not available to other Containers. With the Firefox Multi-Account Containers extension, you can...</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="firefox" /><category term="browser" /><category term="mozilla" /><category term="containers" /><summary type="html">Have you ever got annoyed while using multiple accounts like personal, school, work accounts in a single browser?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/mozilla/firefox-container-f.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/mozilla/firefox-container-f.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Intorducing Mlogs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introducing-mlogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intorducing Mlogs" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/introducing-mlogs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introducing-mlogs/">#### Introducing Mlogs

Mlogs are **mini-blogs** which have read time less than 5 minutes and these are completely mobile friendly.

You can read these mlogs easily using instant view in [telegram](https://t.me/DevsKrate)

### Mlog - **Mini Mobile** friendly **Blogs**

#### Why Mlogs?

![Why Mlogs]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/mlogs/why-mlogs.png)

Being a techster we want to explore more things related to tech and we feel very interesting to keep updated with updated news and applications.

Rather than combining some set of topics in a single blog we want to split these topics into mlogs to keep you updated by spending minimal amount of time.

#### Series of mlogs

There will be different series of mlogs each series will talk about different topics.
&gt; We will make sure that these mlog series will be as interesting as Netflix's web-series.

Our first mlog series will help you to understand better tricks while working with Linux and Commands in it.

Here is our first mlog - [Transferfiles between PC and mobile wirelessly by scanning QR code](https://DevsKrate.com/transfer-files-between-computer-and-mobile-wireless/)

Trust me we are going to help you automate all your routine boring stuff you're doing out there all these days in linux.

So what are you waiting for let's **heist** some knowledge from [DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com)

##### Happy Quarantine 

Please share your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="mlog" /><category term="introduction" /><category term="series" /><summary type="html">Introducing Mlogs</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/mlogs.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/mlogs.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>