<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-25T14:55:46+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DevsKrate</title><subtitle>Here at DevsKrate we inspire and endeavor to share everything about technology like Softwares, Coding, etc., and provide our best about HOW TO tutorials and BEST OF every category in accordance to our knowledge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Configure your VS Code like a pro</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/configure-vscode-like-a-pro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configure your VS Code like a pro" /><published>2020-04-25T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/configure-vscode-like-a-pro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/configure-vscode-like-a-pro/">Being core **Python** and **Java** developers we extensively use VS Code for our project development and use code formatting heavily to enable consistency of code while developing as a team and there are lot of useful extensions which will help you to ease your task and run things on your fingertips.  

### Why Visual Studio Code 
Visual Studio Code combines the simplicity of a source code editor with powerful developer tooling, like IntelliSense code completion and debugging.

First and foremost, it is an editor that gets out of your way. The delightfully frictionless edit-build-debug cycle means less time fiddling with your environment, and more time executing on your ideas.

Here are some Key Benefits of using VS Code - 
* Available on Mac, Linux, and Ofcourse Windows.
* Edit, Build, and Debug very easily.
* Highly configurable - **Open-source project** 
* VS Code also includes great tooling for web technologies such as NodeJS, JSX/React, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Less, and JSON.
* Highly robust and Extensible.
* High availability of industry and community-developed extensions.
* Much loved dark theme

##### Installing Visual Studio Code
We can download updated version of VS Code from their website - [https://code.visualstudio.com/](https://code.visualstudio.com/)

Download from here  - [https://code.visualstudio.com/download](https://code.visualstudio.com/download)

#### Required Extensions for all developers
**1. Python extension by Microsoft** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-python.python)

![Python editing]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/python-editing.gif){:height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;}
- An extension with rich support for the Python language, including features such as linting, debugging, IntelliSense, code navigation, code formatting, refactoring, unit tests, snippets, and more!
* I personally use **black** code-formatter. we can configure it in our workspace settings in **.vscode** file. This helps to maintain code and code-formatting consistent in development.
    -    Troubleshoot the code formatting plugin in python
         [https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/python/editing](https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/python/editing)
         
**2. Java Extension by Mircosoft** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-java-pack)

![ Java ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/java.png){:height=&quot;60px&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot;}
+ Java Extension Pack is a collection of popular extensions that can help write, test and debug Java applications in Visual Studio Code.

**3. Markdown Renderer Extension** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=shd101wyy.markdown-preview-enhanced)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/md-image.png){:height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;}
+ Markdown Preview Enhanced is an extension that provides you with many useful functionalities such as automatic scroll sync, math typesetting, mermaid, PlantUML, pandoc, PDF export, code chunk, presentation writer, etc.

**4. Prettier Extension for JavaScript** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=esbenp.prettier-vscode)

![Pretier]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/prettier.png){:height=&quot;80px&quot; width=&quot;80px&quot;}
+ It enforces a consistent style by parsing your code and re-printing it with its own rules that take the maximum line length into account, wrapping code when necessary.
    
**5. ESLint** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=dbaeumer.vscode-eslint)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/eslint.png){:height=&quot;60px&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot;}
+ This will be useful to check JavaScript and TypeScript errors 
+ The extension uses the ESLint library installed in the opened workspace folder. If the folder doesn't provide one the extension looks for a global install version. If you haven't installed ESLint either locally or globally do so by running `npm install eslint` in the workspace folder for a local install or `npm install -g eslint` for a global install.

**6. CSS Peek** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=pranaygp.vscode-css-peek)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/css.gif){:height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;}
+ CSS Peek is a great tool if you keep forgetting what was a CSS class was used for. However, that could also mean that your CSS class names are not meaningful, or you have written too much &quot;unmaintainable&quot; code. Still, this is sure going to be handy if you are viewing/rewriting someone else’s code. 

**7. Debugger for Chrome** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=msjsdiag.debugger-for-chrome)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/chrome.gif){:height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;}
+ Debugger for Chrome is a great tool if you use a debugger in VSC. It allows you to launch an instance of Chrome navigated to your app, or it can attach to a running instance of Chrome. Using the URL parameter, you tell VSC which URL to either open or launch in Chrome.

**8. Gitlens** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=eamodio.gitlens)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/git-lens.png){:height=&quot;60px&quot; width=&quot;37%&quot;}
+ GitLens supercharges the Git capabilities built into Visual Studio Code. It helps you to visualize code authorship at a glance via Git blame annotations and code lens, seamlessly navigate and explore Git repositories, gain valuable insights via powerful comparison commands, and so much more.

**9. Git File History** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=pomber.git-file-history)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/git-file-history.gif){:height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;}
+ This helps to quickly browse the history (edits and commits done by you and others) in a cool and interesting visualization. 
+ you can try this in browser also. you just need to do these three steps.
    1. Go to a file in GitHub (or GitLab, or Bitbucket)
    2. Replace github.com with github.githistory.xyz
    3. There's no step three. you'll love this.

**10. Docker Extension** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-azuretools.vscode-docker)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/docker.png){:height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;}
+ The Docker extension makes it easier to build apps that leverage Docker containers. The extension helps scaffold needed files, build Docker images, debug your app inside a container, and an explorer that makes it easy to take actions on containers and images such as start, stop, inspect, remove, and more.

**11. SQL Formatter** - [download](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=bradymholt.pgformatter)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/sql.png){:height=&quot;60px&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot;}
+ This VS Code extension formats PostgreSQL SQL, using the Perl based [pgFormatter](https://github.com/darold/pgFormatter) tool. Supports keywords from SQL-92, SQL-99, SQL-2003, SQL-2008, SQL-2011 and PostgreSQL specifics keywords. Provides configuration to control formatting style.

**12. Path Intellisense** - [downlaod](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=christian-kohler.path-intellisense)

![Markdown gif]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/vscode/path-intelli.png){:height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;}
+ Path Intellisense helps you include filenames or autocomplete them. This is a great tool if you want to type less for difficult filenames and make sure you always include the correct files.

#### Not just this many more to come in future
Please share your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at support@devskrate.com. Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="developers" /><category term="microsoft" /><category term="vscode" /><category term="DevStuff" /><category term="configuring" /><summary type="html">Being core Python and Java developers we extensively use VS Code for our project development and use code formatting heavily to enable consistency of code while developing as a team and there are lot of useful extensions which will help you to ease your task and run things on your fingertips.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/vscode/vscode-home.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/vscode/vscode-home.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ubuntu 20 booting problems.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ubuntu20-booting-problems/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ubuntu 20 booting problems." /><published>2020-04-25T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ubuntu20-booting-problems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ubuntu20-booting-problems/">&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 20 LTS has been released recently, after upgrading to it from ubuntu 18, 19, many had may faced booting problems(especially in DualBoot’s).
Booting problems like bootloop(Restarting when ubuntu is selected) or blank screen after selecting ubuntu in the grub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With My experience, I am giving here few fixes you may try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Uncheck the PPT security in BIOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly goto the BIOS (It depends on the system, for Dell press F12), then goto security, then goto PTT security and Uncheck it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Security -&amp;gt; PTT Security and uncheck PTT On
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click Apply (I would recommend choosing Save as Custom User Settings), then OK, then Exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should acctuallly work. If this does not work, try the second method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Boot from Advanced Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While booting from grub, you can see “Advanced Options for Ubuntu”. Select it and in that boot from the Old Kernel.
You may find many things like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu, with Linux 5.4-generic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu, with Linux 5.4-generic (recovery mode)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu, with Linux 4.*-generic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu, with Linux 4.*-generic (recovery mode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boot with Linux 4.*-generic, don’t boot with recovery or any other options availabe additionally.
Now, you will boot into Ubuntu:).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, this method is not a permanent fix, you can use Ubuntu inthis way as long as you find the permanent fix, this will not do anything from accessing all the features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Info&lt;/strong&gt;: Why method 2 is not a permanent fix, because Ubuntu uses Linux kernel 5.4, so grub will boot from it by default. After booting in you can change the default kernel to boot, but be carefull while handling with the Kernel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="ubuntu" /><category term="linux" /><category term="kernel" /><category term="intel" /><category term="os" /><summary type="html">Ubuntu 20 LTS has been released recently, after upgrading to it from ubuntu 18, 19, many had may faced booting problems(especially in DualBoot’s). Booting problems like bootloop(Restarting when ubuntu is selected) or blank screen after selecting ubuntu in the grub.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/ubuntu-clogo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/ubuntu-clogo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New iPhones Might Delay Due To the Pandemic Says The Famous Apple Analyst : Ming-Chi Kuo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/iphones-delay-in-release/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New iPhones Might Delay Due To the Pandemic Says The Famous Apple Analyst : Ming-Chi Kuo" /><published>2020-04-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/iphones-delay-in-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/iphones-delay-in-release/">Analyst Ming-Chi Kuo, In his new investor note, has outlined some information regarding the possible delay of the iPhone 12's production as well as the possible postponement of its much-rumored iPhone SE plus due to the Coronavirus pandemic.

# iPhone 12 production:
In Kuo's note, He said that due to the pandemic caused by COVID-19, The Cupertino giant(Apple) had to do a lot of changes in its production, which lead to a one-month delay in engineering verification testing for the new iPhone 12 models.

The iPhone 12 lineup is expected to include four new models, and According to the analyst
the lower end models sized 6.1- inch and 5.4-inch iPhone will enter into the mass production in September
and the 6.7 inch which is expected to come with 5G support will enter not enter the production until October.
According to Kuo,this is because the 6.7-inch model has the most complicated design.

The above could mean that Apple will announce all the four iPhone models at once
but the release dates likely going to be different for each model due to the production delays.

# iPhone SE Plus Delayed:

iPhone SE 2020 has sold more models than Apple expected and there were strong rumors
regarding a plus model of the iPhone SE and was confirmed by the evidences found in the IOS 14 code
however Kuo's note says that the iPhone SE Plus is likely to be delayed until Q2 2021.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="apple" /><category term="iphone" /><summary type="html">Analyst Ming-Chi Kuo, In his new investor note, has outlined some information regarding the possible delay of the iPhone 12’s production as well as the possible postponement of its much-rumored iPhone SE plus due to the Coronavirus pandemic. iPhone 12 production: In Kuo’s note, He said that due to the pandemic caused by COVID-19, The Cupertino giant(Apple) had to do a lot of changes in its production, which lead to a one-month delay in engineering verification testing for the new iPhone 12 models. The iPhone 12 lineup is expected to include four new models, and According to the analyst the lower end models sized 6.1- inch and 5.4-inch iPhone will enter into the mass production in September and the 6.7 inch which is expected to come with 5G support will enter not enter the production until October. According to Kuo,this is because the 6.7-inch model has the most complicated design. The above could mean that Apple will announce all the four iPhone models at once but the release dates likely going to be different for each model due to the production delays. iPhone SE Plus Delayed: iPhone SE 2020 has sold more models than Apple expected and there were strong rumors regarding a plus model of the iPhone SE and was confirmed by the evidences found in the IOS 14 code however Kuo’s note says that the iPhone SE Plus is likely to be delayed until Q2 2021.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/iphone-12-renders.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/iphone-12-renders.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Motorolo launches its new edge series in states:</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/moto-edge-series/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Motorolo launches its new edge series in states:" /><published>2020-04-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/moto-edge-series</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/moto-edge-series/">Moto after 4 years has come back to making flagship phones with its new edge series, 
It launched two phones namely Moto Edge and Moto Edge Plus. Let's see what Motorola has to offer 
in this article.

# Moto Edge Plus:
The standout feature of this phone has to be its design, It's 
an all-glass display with metal frame holding them together, The 
edges wrap around the edges with a punch hole at the top and in 
one word it looks gorgeous with two color variants to offer namely midnight 
megneta and solar black. Before 
taking a deep dive lets see the specs.

Processor:	Qualcomm Snapdragon 865
Rear Camera	Triple Cameras 108MP(with OIS) + 16MP(Ultra Wide + Macro) + 8MP(3x Zoom with OIS)
front Camera	25MP
Display	        6.7 inches 90HZ AMOLED(Aspect ratio: 21:9) FHD
5G support	both mm and sub-6 band.
Battery	        5000mAH(18W)
Fingerprint	In-Display Fingerprint Sensor(Optical)
Water Resistant	Water Resistant(IP 68)
Charging	Type-C cable + Wireless Charging(Upto 15W) + 5W(Reverse Wireless Charging)
RAM/ROM         12GB/128or256GB

# Display and battery:  
The display is a 6.7 inch AMOLED display with an aspect ratio of 21:9 and the phone comes with a 90HZ refresh rate but the resolution is only FHD(1080p), which is a bummer at this price point but it helps increase the battery efficiency and in 
this phone moto has provided a huge 5000mAh battery and moto claims it can last till 2 days.

# Camera:
This phone comes with a total of four cameras three at the back and one inside the punch hole. The primary sensor is a 108MP 
Samsung sensor which we saw in the galaxy s20 ultra, This camera by default shoots at 27MP and it has OIS built-in for stable video.The 
second sensory is an 8MP three times zoom sensor and this also has OIS for better video as well as zoom. The third is a 16MP Ultra wide sensor to capture ultra-wide shots.The selfie camera is a 25MP shooter. This phone has all the hardware required for a good camera it ultimately comes down to
camera software.

# Software and Hardware:
Talking about software, It comes with an almost stock-like experience with a few added features based on android 10, and moto is calling it &quot;My UX&quot;.In days where flagship smartphones are removing the headphone jack moto has it in this phone which is a great thing.
The hardware also is top end with snapdragon 865, It also supports fast charging, wireless charging, reverse wireless charging 
and all other high-end features to compete against the top of galaxies and iPhones.

# Pricing:
This phone is priced at 999.99 dollars which converts to around 75k price, which is very expensive considering what this phone has to offer.
If moto really wants to bring this phone to India it has to reduce the price to somewhere around 55k. 

# Moto Edge:
Edge is very similar to Edge plus with very few changes. The main shooter is 64MP instead of 108MP, the battery capacity is 4500mAH instead of 5000mAH, It 
only offers 4GB/6GB of RAM and it does not support any kind of wireless and reverse wireless charging on it but the key 
difference is that it comes with snapdragon 765 5G on board.This phone is priced at 699 EURO, which is 58,000 rupees. I think this phone is fairly overpriced and at this price we can get several other options
from vendors like one plus, Xiaomi, etc, which can offer us a flagship experience.    

Both these phones are expected to launch in India after the pandemic has ended,what do you think about these phones</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="moto" /><category term="flagship" /><summary type="html">Moto after 4 years has come back to making flagship phones with its new edge series, It launched two phones namely Moto Edge and Moto Edge Plus. Let’s see what Motorola has to offer in this article.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/android/motorola-edge.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/android/motorola-edge.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple iPhone SE 2020 is ready!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/apple-iphone-se/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple iPhone SE 2020 is ready!" /><published>2020-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/apple-iphone-se</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple-iphone-se/">## Hey Folks! ##
All the wait is over. Finally,the Apple iPhone SE 2020 is ready for competition.  
The most awaited iPhone SE has been scilently released by Apple into it's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/apple/se-size-img.png&quot; alt=&quot;iPhone SE 2020&quot; title=&quot;iPhone SE 2020&quot; /&gt;

## Tech Specs:
**Colors:** Available in three Colors. **Black, White, Product RED**  
**Capacity: 64GB, 128GB, 256GB**  
**Size and Weight:**  
Height: 5.45 inches (138.4 mm)  
Width : 2.65 inches (67.3 mm)  
Depth : 0.29 inch (7.3 mm)  
Weight: 5.22 ounces (148 grams)  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/apple/se-size-weight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iPhone SE Size&quot; title=&quot;iPhone SE 2020 Size&quot; /&gt;

**Display: 4.7&quot;**  
&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/apple/se-display.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iPhone SE Display&quot; title=&quot;iPhone SE 2020 Display&quot; /&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;b&gt;    Retina HD display
    4.7-inch (diagonal) widescreen LCD Multi‑Touch display with IPS technology
    1334-by-750-pixel resolution at 326 ppi
    1400:1 contrast ratio (typical)
    True Tone display
    Wide color display (P3)
    Haptic Touch
    625 nits max brightness (typical)
    Fingerprint-resistant oleophobic coating
    Display Zoom
    Reachability&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

**Chip: A13 Bionic chip (Third‑generation Neural Engine)**   

**Splash, Water, and Dust Resistant: Rated IP67 (maximum depth of 1 meter up to 30 minutes) under IEC standard 60529**  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/apple/se-camera.jpg&quot; title=&quot;iPhone SE 2020 Camera Specs&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/apple/se-video.jpg&quot; title=&quot;iPhone SE 2020 Video Specs&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/apple/se-frntcamera.jpg&quot; title=&quot;iPhone SE 2020 Front Camera Specs&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/apple/se-addl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

**Pricing Details:** Starts from $399(approx. ₹30549) to $549(approx. ₹42034)

There is no any fixed date of launch in India due to the COVID-19 Lockdown, but will be launched very soon.

For more details check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-se/specs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Product Page&lt;/a&gt;

**Conclusion**: This new iphone is basically the internals of iphone 11 in an iPhone 8 body. This is the one of the cheapest way to enter into the iOS eco-system. This is best suited as a second phone or a testing device for developing iOS apps.</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="iPhone" /><category term="SE" /><category term="Apple" /><summary type="html">Hey Folks! All the wait is over. Finally,the Apple iPhone SE 2020 is ready for competition. The most awaited iPhone SE has been scilently released by Apple into it’s website. Tech Specs: Colors: Available in three Colors. Black, White, Product RED Capacity: 64GB, 128GB, 256GB Size and Weight: Height: 5.45 inches (138.4 mm) Width : 2.65 inches (67.3 mm) Depth : 0.29 inch (7.3 mm) Weight: 5.22 ounces (148 grams) Display: 4.7” Retina HD display 4.7-inch (diagonal) widescreen LCD Multi‑Touch display with IPS technology 1334-by-750-pixel resolution at 326 ppi 1400:1 contrast ratio (typical) True Tone display Wide color display (P3) Haptic Touch 625 nits max brightness (typical) Fingerprint-resistant oleophobic coating Display Zoom Reachability Chip: A13 Bionic chip (Third‑generation Neural Engine) Splash, Water, and Dust Resistant: Rated IP67 (maximum depth of 1 meter up to 30 minutes) under IEC standard 60529 Pricing Details: Starts from $399(approx. ₹30549) to $549(approx. ₹42034) There is no any fixed date of launch in India due to the COVID-19 Lockdown, but will be launched very soon. For more details check the Product Page Conclusion: This new iphone is basically the internals of iphone 11 in an iPhone 8 body. This is the one of the cheapest way to enter into the iOS eco-system. This is best suited as a second phone or a testing device for developing iOS apps.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/se-ftre.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/se-ftre.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One Plus 8 pro - The Real Flagship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/one-plus-8-pro-spec/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Plus 8 pro - The Real Flagship" /><published>2020-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/one-plus-8-pro-spec</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/one-plus-8-pro-spec/">It has been 6 years since one plus has been making smartphones until last year the company has produced a lot of flagship killer but the company from the past year has changed its strategy to produce a true flagship with its one plus 7 pro and 7t pro they were good but lacked the bells and whistles that a true flagship from samsung and apple had. With this phone one plus is trying 
to tick all the boxes of a flagship. Did it succeed, let's see in the article below.

**Before taking a deep dive into the phones, let's see what specs this phone has to offer:**

{:class=&quot;table table-bordered dark&quot;}
|Name            | Specifications                                                            |
| -----------    | ------------------------------------------------------------------------  |
|Processor       | Qualcomm Snapdragon 865                                                   |
|Rear Camera     | Quad Cameras 48MP(f/178) + 48MP(Ultra Wide) + 8MP(3x Zoom) + 5MP(Color Sensor)  |
|front Camera    | 16MP                                                                      |
|Display         | 6.78 inches 120HZ AMOLED(Aspect ratio:19.8:9)                             |
|Connectivity    | 5G, WIFI 6 Support                                                         |
|Battery         | 4510mAH(30T warp charging)                                                |
|Fingerprint     | In-Display Fingerprint Sensor(Optical)                                    |
|Water Resistant | Water Resistant(IP 68)                                                    |
|Charging        | Type-C cable + Wireless Charging(Upto 30W) + 3W(Reverse Wireless Charging)|

If you have carefully observed the specs, this phone includes an IP Rating as well as wireless charging.
This shows that one plus is not trying to cut corners against the best of samsung and apple but instead giving it all to take them head on.

* The phone pricing in India is not out yet but if we consider the US pricing which is 899$ 
converting it into INR we can estimate the price to be at around 68k with this price it 
still manages to undercut the iphone 11 and galaxy s20.

* Talking about the design, it has a single punch hole curved display similar to galaxy s10.
* The highlight of this phone has to be its **120Hz AMOLED** display which DisplayMate rated as an A+ display.(For people who are unaware of DisplayMate its like DXO Mark for Displays).

![2020 oneplus 8 ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/oneplus/oneplus8-pro-front.jpg)

* Coming to the camera its a quad camera setup and on paper can take on the other flagships nicely.
* The Build quality with its glass body attached together by a metal has always been good but this time it also added dust and water resistance which is rated as IP 68(fit enough to withstand dust, dirt and sand and are resistant to submersion up to a maximum depth of 1.5m underwater for up to thirty minutes).

![2020 oneplus 8 ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/oneplus/oneplus8-pro-f-b.jpg)

* Taking about battery life, this phone comes with a 4510mAH capacity which is fairly good enough.

The performance is also great coming with snapdragon 865 processor.
This phone also supports 5G and WIFI 6 making it a future proof phone. The software thats the oxygen OS gives the cleanest andriod experience.

**Conclusion**: One Plus ended up making a really appealing flagship smartphone undercutting the likes samsung and apple by a good margin and offering way more specifications at this price point.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="oneplus" /><category term="android" /><category term="google" /><summary type="html">It has been 6 years since one plus has been making smartphones until last year the company has produced a lot of flagship killer but the company from the past year has changed its strategy to produce a true flagship with its one plus 7 pro and 7t pro they were good but lacked the bells and whistles that a true flagship from samsung and apple had. With this phone one plus is trying to tick all the boxes of a flagship. Did it succeed, let’s see in the article below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oneplus/oneplus8-pro-display.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oneplus/oneplus8-pro-display.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One Plus 8 - Flagship Killer or Wallet Killer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/one-plus-8-spec/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Plus 8 - Flagship Killer or Wallet Killer" /><published>2020-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/one-plus-8-spec</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/one-plus-8-spec/">One Plus is now 6 years in smartphone making.Its strategy was always to launch a phone that brought with it a flagship experience but not so expensive as a flagship but as years passed by its pricing 
kept on increasing from generation to generation. So, is this new One plus 8 a &quot;flagship killer or a wallet killer&quot;, lets find out in this article.

+ Lets talk specs for a while, it's powered by the top of the line Qualcomm's Snapdragon 865 processor, which comes with a 6.55 inches AMOLED with a 90HZ refresh rate, which DisplayMate rated as an A+ display.(For people who are unaware of display mate its like DXO Mark for Displays).
+ Coming to the camera its a triple camera setup the main sensory and the wide angle are the same found on the one plus 7t which are 48MP and 16MP respectively and the third sensor is replaced by a macro lens to capture closeup shots. The selfie shooter is a 16MP sensor which is the same one found on the one plus 7t. The battery capacity is 4300 mAh.

![2020 oneplus 8 ]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/oneplus/oneplus8-f-b.jpg)

- The phones pricing in India at this point of time is unknown but if we consider the price of 
this phone in US,We can expect a price at about 53,000 Rupees which is almost 13,000 price increase from the one plus 7t which was 37,999 rupees at launch.

- The 13k price increase brings a new design change to the front which is punch hole display with curved edges(similar to the one found in the galaxy s10). The same old 90hZ display which is much brighter for better outdoor use.

The phones also comes with a slightly improved stereo speakers setup with dolby atmos support.The standout feature of this phone has to be the support for 5G and wifi 6.



**Conclusion:** I think that one plus, for this time has ended up making a wallet killer. If what you really want 5G we have much cheaper options from namely the realme X50 and if you want the smooth experience of oxygen OS. The older one plus phones namely the 7t can give you the same experience for much lesser price. One plus 8 is meant for people whose first priority is design, oxygen OS and 5G in a single package.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="oneplus" /><category term="android" /><category term="google" /><summary type="html">One Plus is now 6 years in smartphone making.Its strategy was always to launch a phone that brought with it a flagship experience but not so expensive as a flagship but as years passed by its pricing kept on increasing from generation to generation. So, is this new One plus 8 a “flagship killer or a wallet killer”, lets find out in this article.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oneplus/oneplus8-display.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oneplus/oneplus8-display.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[update: India Specific Site]Google’s coronavirus website finally launches alongside enhanced search results</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-coronavirus-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[update: India Specific Site]Google’s coronavirus website finally launches alongside enhanced search results" /><published>2020-04-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google%20coronavirus-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-coronavirus-website/">Google had launched a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/covid19/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;India specific Caronavirus site&lt;/a&gt; containing Health Information, Safety and precautions tips, Data &amp; Insighs and Resources to help. It also contains National helpline toll free numbers. The site also contains state wise caronavirus infected list.
**[update ends]😊✌**

**21 March, 2020**
One week ago, President Donald Trump held a press conference wherein he claimed Google would be building a screening website for the coronavirus that would direct people to testing sites. As we learned in the following days, that wasn’t true. Google’s sister company Verily did launch such a site, but only for the Bay Area and reportedly it only offered tests to a very small number of people. Google, however, did say it would launch some sort of website and after a small delay, it’s here.

Alongside the website and potentially more importantly, Google will start providing more enhanced information cards for people who search for terms related to the coronavirus. There will be information tabs for symptoms, prevention, global statics, and locally relevant information. It will look a bit like this:
&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/google/COVID_19_MOBILE_SEARCH.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;near by hospitals search result&quot;/&gt;

The website is at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/covid19&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;google.com/covid19&lt;/a&gt;. It does have useful resources, including a card that mimics what you see above. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/search/connecting-people-covid-19-information-and-resources&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google’s post announcing the site&lt;/a&gt; says that you will be able to find “state-based information, safety and prevention tips, search trends related to COVID-19, and further resources for individuals, educators and businesses.” Google emphasizes that it’s pulling information from “authoritative” sources like the WHO and the CDC.

It’s only available in English right now, but a Google spokesperson tells The Verge that Spanish language support is soon to follow. The site was also designed with accessibility in mind, including with the larger fonts that Google usually uses.

The website has videos in ASL, a global map showing confirmed cases by country, and plenty of information about Google’s other relief efforts — plus some feel-good YouTube videos.

Reading through that description, however, you’ll notice that it doesn’t include what Trump originally claimed it would. The nearest thing to finding a test is a drop-down menu that provides links to local websites — for example, choosing California provides a link to the California Department of Public Health.

Right now, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/symptoms-testing/testing.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CDC has a “self-checker” chatbot&lt;/a&gt; that Microsoft helped build, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/coronavirus/card/ih47JgriBzLY0nXEbncs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WSJ quoted an executive from a healthcare provider&lt;/a&gt; who put in a realistic context: “It’s just something consumers need now to help with anxiety.”

In other words, lots of big tech companies are making efforts to provide coronavirus-related support, but none of them are able to solve some of the biggest problems in the pandemic: access to testing and the impending crisis in our healthcare infrastructure.

At some point in the future, Google may actually provide a questionnaire and information about local drive-thru testing locations. But a spokesperson says that the company won’t do so until there’s authoritative and trustworthy information on those sites. That could be a long time coming, unfortunately.</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="corona virus" /><category term="google" /><category term="outbreak" /><category term="general" /><summary type="html">Google had launched a new India specific Caronavirus site containing Health Information, Safety and precautions tips, Data &amp;amp; Insighs and Resources to help. It also contains National helpline toll free numbers. The site also contains state wise caronavirus infected list. [update ends]😊✌ 21 March, 2020 One week ago, President Donald Trump held a press conference wherein he claimed Google would be building a screening website for the coronavirus that would direct people to testing sites. As we learned in the following days, that wasn’t true. Google’s sister company Verily did launch such a site, but only for the Bay Area and reportedly it only offered tests to a very small number of people. Google, however, did say it would launch some sort of website and after a small delay, it’s here. Alongside the website and potentially more importantly, Google will start providing more enhanced information cards for people who search for terms related to the coronavirus. There will be information tabs for symptoms, prevention, global statics, and locally relevant information. It will look a bit like this: The website is at google.com/covid19. It does have useful resources, including a card that mimics what you see above. Google’s post announcing the site says that you will be able to find “state-based information, safety and prevention tips, search trends related to COVID-19, and further resources for individuals, educators and businesses.” Google emphasizes that it’s pulling information from “authoritative” sources like the WHO and the CDC. It’s only available in English right now, but a Google spokesperson tells The Verge that Spanish language support is soon to follow. The site was also designed with accessibility in mind, including with the larger fonts that Google usually uses. The website has videos in ASL, a global map showing confirmed cases by country, and plenty of information about Google’s other relief efforts — plus some feel-good YouTube videos. Reading through that description, however, you’ll notice that it doesn’t include what Trump originally claimed it would. The nearest thing to finding a test is a drop-down menu that provides links to local websites — for example, choosing California provides a link to the California Department of Public Health. Right now, the CDC has a “self-checker” chatbot that Microsoft helped build, but the WSJ quoted an executive from a healthcare provider who put in a realistic context: “It’s just something consumers need now to help with anxiety.” In other words, lots of big tech companies are making efforts to provide coronavirus-related support, but none of them are able to solve some of the biggest problems in the pandemic: access to testing and the impending crisis in our healthcare infrastructure. At some point in the future, Google may actually provide a questionnaire and information about local drive-thru testing locations. But a spokesperson says that the company won’t do so until there’s authoritative and trustworthy information on those sites. That could be a long time coming, unfortunately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/COVID_19_Information___Resources___Google.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/COVID_19_Information___Resources___Google.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google is shutting down its Neighbourly app</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-is-shutting-down-its-neighbourly-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google is shutting down its Neighbourly app" /><published>2020-04-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-is-shutting-down-its-neighbourly-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-is-shutting-down-its-neighbourly-app/">Google is killing another one of its experimental apps — Neighbourly. The company said it’s shutting down the app on May 12, as the project didn’t take off as expected.  

The search giant first unveiled the app in May 2018 as a test in the Indian city of Mumbai to let you explore your neighborhood with help from local experts. Later in November, it expanded its base to a few more cities in the country. However, it failed to gain traction, likely because it simply didn’t have enough users to deliver an engaging experience. It never even came out of beta.  

In an email sent to customers, Google mentioned that the community answered over a million questions related to their localities, but the project didn’t grow the way the company had hoped:  

&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#EEEEEE&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;We launched Neighbourly as a Beta app to connect you with your neighbors and make sharing local information more human and helpful. As a community, you’ve come together to celebrate local festivals, shared crucial information during floods, and answered over a million questions.&lt;/i&gt;  
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But Neighbourly hasn’t grown as we had hoped. In these difficult times, we believe that we can help more people by focusing on other Google apps that are already serving millions of people everyday.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Google also pointed towards &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.google.com/localguides&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Maps Local Guide&lt;/a&gt; to help people in your region find answers related to the area.

The announcement comes at an interesting time: &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/news/2020/03/coronavirus/#Community-Help&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook just rolled out a ‘community help’ feature&lt;/a&gt; for people to request or offer assistance in their neighborhoods during the coronavirus crisis.

The app is closing down on May 12; you’ll be able to download your Neighbourly content until October 12. Another one for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://killedbygoogle.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Graveyard&lt;/a&gt;.

Post Credit: The Next Web</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="google" /><category term="neighbourly" /><category term="apps" /><summary type="html">Google is killing another one of its experimental apps — Neighbourly. The company said it’s shutting down the app on May 12, as the project didn’t take off as expected. The search giant first unveiled the app in May 2018 as a test in the Indian city of Mumbai to let you explore your neighborhood with help from local experts. Later in November, it expanded its base to a few more cities in the country. However, it failed to gain traction, likely because it simply didn’t have enough users to deliver an engaging experience. It never even came out of beta. In an email sent to customers, Google mentioned that the community answered over a million questions related to their localities, but the project didn’t grow the way the company had hoped: We launched Neighbourly as a Beta app to connect you with your neighbors and make sharing local information more human and helpful. As a community, you’ve come together to celebrate local festivals, shared crucial information during floods, and answered over a million questions. But Neighbourly hasn’t grown as we had hoped. In these difficult times, we believe that we can help more people by focusing on other Google apps that are already serving millions of people everyday. Google also pointed towards Google Maps Local Guide to help people in your region find answers related to the area. The announcement comes at an interesting time: Facebook just rolled out a ‘community help’ feature for people to request or offer assistance in their neighborhoods during the coronavirus crisis. The app is closing down on May 12; you’ll be able to download your Neighbourly content until October 12. Another one for the Google Graveyard. Post Credit: The Next Web</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/neighbourly.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/neighbourly.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to find trending apps in any country</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-to-find-trending-apps-in-any-coutry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to find trending apps in any country" /><published>2020-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-to-find-trending-apps-in-any-coutry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-to-find-trending-apps-in-any-coutry/">Usually, to gain insight into what’s trending on the app stores, I either read prominent websites or look at the trending page on the app store. However, the problem arises when you have to look for global data. For instance, I am located in India and if I have to check what’s trending on the US Play Store, I would have to change my Google account location. Tedious! Recently, I stumbled upon a website that lets you check the trending apps in every country and even the app trend.

It is quite helpful if you are an app developer and want to understand the trend of the market. It’s also helpful if you are a journalist who covers technology and currently trending apps. It helps you gauge the type of apps that are becoming popular within different countries and regions.

## How to find trending apps in any country?

Head over to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.similarweb.com/apps/top/google/app-index/us/all/top-free&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Similar Web tool&lt;/a&gt; and select the country. For instance, I have selected the United States as the country whose trending apps I want to see. Now, click on the “Go” button on the extreme right side. You will see the list of apps that are currently trending on the Google Play Store.

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/apps/play_store.png&quot; title=&quot;Play Store Leader Board&quot;/&gt;

The website also lets you see trending apps on the Apple Play Store. In the first drop-down, you can select the store as “Apple App Store” and let other options as default. Click on the go button and it will populate the trending apps on the Apple store. Additionally,  you will also see an “iPad/iPhone” toggle on just below the Go button.

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/apps/app_store.png&quot; title=&quot;App Store Leader Board&quot;/&gt;

There are a couple of different filters besides the App Store and the country. You can filter out apps based on categories like Fitness, Music, Productivity, etc. Moroever, you have a control to view popular paid apps as well.

Additionally, the website shows you app trends as well. It’s a separate tab with multiple sections on it. One of the sections shows you apps that have become recently become popular and are new in the top 100 list. In addition to that, there’s a section that shows apps that have climbed their way and have increased their ranking in the top 100.

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/apps/app_trends.png&quot; title=&quot;App Trends&quot;/&gt;

Another popular app research tool is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appbrain.com/info/ranking&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AppBrain&lt;/a&gt;. In comparison, Similar Web doesn’t show you trends for an individual app, the number of downloads, etc. On the other hand, AppBrain is a furthermore intensive app data website. But, having said that if you write or develop apps, these 2 websites are a must-have bookmark on your browser.</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="internet" /><category term="play store" /><category term="app store" /><category term="trending" /><category term="app ranking" /><summary type="html">Usually, to gain insight into what’s trending on the app stores, I either read prominent websites or look at the trending page on the app store. However, the problem arises when you have to look for global data. For instance, I am located in India and if I have to check what’s trending on the US Play Store, I would have to change my Google account location. Tedious! Recently, I stumbled upon a website that lets you check the trending apps in every country and even the app trend. It is quite helpful if you are an app developer and want to understand the trend of the market. It’s also helpful if you are a journalist who covers technology and currently trending apps. It helps you gauge the type of apps that are becoming popular within different countries and regions. How to find trending apps in any country? Head over to this Similar Web tool and select the country. For instance, I have selected the United States as the country whose trending apps I want to see. Now, click on the “Go” button on the extreme right side. You will see the list of apps that are currently trending on the Google Play Store. The website also lets you see trending apps on the Apple Play Store. In the first drop-down, you can select the store as “Apple App Store” and let other options as default. Click on the go button and it will populate the trending apps on the Apple store. Additionally, you will also see an “iPad/iPhone” toggle on just below the Go button. There are a couple of different filters besides the App Store and the country. You can filter out apps based on categories like Fitness, Music, Productivity, etc. Moroever, you have a control to view popular paid apps as well. Additionally, the website shows you app trends as well. It’s a separate tab with multiple sections on it. One of the sections shows you apps that have become recently become popular and are new in the top 100 list. In addition to that, there’s a section that shows apps that have climbed their way and have increased their ranking in the top 100. Another popular app research tool is AppBrain. In comparison, Similar Web doesn’t show you trends for an individual app, the number of downloads, etc. On the other hand, AppBrain is a furthermore intensive app data website. But, having said that if you write or develop apps, these 2 websites are a must-have bookmark on your browser.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apps/trernding_apps.jfif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apps/trernding_apps.jfif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>