<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-27T21:44:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DevsKrate</title><subtitle>Here at DevsKrate we inspire and endeavor to share everything about technology like Softwares, Coding, etc., and provide our best about HOW TO tutorials and BEST OF every category in accordance to our knowledge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">REALME Launched 32, 43 inch smart TV in India starting at Rs 12,999</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/realmetv-specs-and-price/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="REALME Launched 32, 43 inch smart TV in India starting at Rs 12,999" /><published>2020-05-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/realmetv-specs-and-price</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/realmetv-specs-and-price/">Realme, famously known for its smartphones, has started expanding its portfolio, and this time its the new Realme Smart Tv. This smart tv comes in two sizes the 32 and the 43-inch. The main differentiator apart from size is that the 32 inch comes with an HD screen whereas the 43-inch comes with a full HD, while the rest of the specifications remain the same.


#### Display:
Realme's tv as mentioned above comes in at two sizes namely the 32 and the 43 inch. These **LED Back-Light displays** comes with chroma boost picture engine to enhance the overall picture quality and improve the brightness, color, contrast, and clarity to deliver stunning visuals. The TV supports up to 400 nits of brightness and up to 178-degree viewing angles. It also has support HDR 10 and HLG and it offers seven display modes starting from standard, sport, movie, user, energy-saving, game to vivid mode for more customized picture quality.

![RealmeTV Display]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/2020-realmetv-display.png)

#### Design:
The stand-out feature of this Tv has to be its design. It comes an almost bezel-less design, which Realme is calling **Premium Bezel-less Design**. The size of the bezel is as thin as 8.7mm on the top and around the sides, but the bottom bezel is a bit thicker and it houses the realme logo. You can either prop up the TV or wall-mount it, that's entirely up to your choice.

![RealmeTV Design]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realmetv-design.jpg)

#### Software:
This smart TV comes with **Andriod TV 9.0**, which is Google’s latest OS for television sets. There are no additional skins on top and that's a good thing. It comes with Youtube, Prime Video, Netflix, and Live TV pre-installed. You can also download more apps and games from the play store. It also comes with chrome-cast built-in,to syn content of your phone with the TV. Since it is an android TV, It also comes with google assistant of hands-free voice commands.

![RealmeTV Android TV 9.0]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realmeTV-software.jpg)

#### Internals:
Powering this TV is the quad-core 64-bit MediaTek chipset (featuring ARM Cortex A53 CPU, clocked at up to 1.1GHz) and Mali-470 MP3 GPU. It comes with 1GB of RAM and 8GB of ROM. The TV comes with a 24W quad-speaker(2 speakers and 2 tweeters) with Dolby Audio support for rich sound stage.

#### Ports and Connectivity:
Speaking about connectivity it comes with 2.4GHZ WIFI, Bluetooth 5.0, and more. The fact that this does not come with WIFI 5 standard is a bit of a letdown.

![RealmeTV Ports]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realmeTV-ports.jpg)

This TV  comes with a decent port selection, 3x HDMI, 2x USB, 1x Ethernet, 1x SPDIF, 1x AV port, 1x antenna in port, and a 3.5mm audio jack. 

#### Realme Smart TV: Remote
The remote looks similar to another smart remote from XIAOMI and ONE PLUS. It comes with a power On/Off button, a mute button, a Circular button for navigation at the top.below the circular button is the back, home, and settings button. Below them are the quick buttons for Netflix, YouTube, and Prime Video. It also comes with assistant button for quick voice commands and a plus, minus buttons to the left and right side of it, to increase and decrease volume. It can be operated both via the infrared and Bluetooth.

![RealmeTV Smart Remote]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/realme/realmetv-remote.jpg)

#### Price and Availability:
The 32-inch Realme Smart TV is priced at Rs. 12,999 whereas the 43-inch variant is priced at Rs. 21,999 for the larger screen and higher resolution. These smart TVs will go on sale starting from 2nd June on Flipkart and Realme’s website.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="Realme" /><category term="SmartTV" /><category term="AndroidTv" /><summary type="html">Realme, famously known for its smartphones, has started expanding its portfolio, and this time its the new Realme Smart Tv. This smart tv comes in two sizes the 32 and the 43-inch. The main differentiator apart from size is that the 32 inch comes with an HD screen whereas the 43-inch comes with a full HD, while the rest of the specifications remain the same.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/realmetv-main.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/realmetv-main.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">GitHub CLI - Enhance your command line experience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/github-cli-beta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GitHub CLI - Enhance your command line experience" /><published>2020-05-26T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/github-cli-beta</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/github-cli-beta/">Here is an easier and more seamless way to work with GitHub from the command line — [GitHub CLI](https://cli.github.com/), currently it is in **beta**. Millions of developers rely on GitHub for software development to make it more fun and collaborative.
The tool `gh` brings the [GitHub](https://github.com/) experience right to your terminal.


#### Installation 
You can install GitHub CLI today on most of the Operating Systems available -
- macOS     
- Windows     
- Linux     

Install this from [here](https://github.com/cli/cli#installation-and-upgrading)

It’s available today for GitHub Team and Enterprise Cloud, but not yet available for GitHub Enterprise Server. This will have support support for Enterprise Server when it’s out of beta.

#### How to use?
`gh` currently suppports with `issues` and `pull requests` because many developers use them every day. Here are few examples provided by GitHub on how `gh` can improve your experience when contributing to an open source project.

- #####  Filter lists to your needs
    Find an open source project you want to contribute to and clone the repository. And then, to see where maintainers want community contributions, use `gh` to **filter the issues** to only show those with `help-wanted` labels.

    ![gh-example1]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/github/gh-cli1.png)

- #####  Quickly view the details
    Find an **issue** describing a bug that seems like something you can fix, and use `gh` to quickly open it in the browser to get all the details you need to get started. 
         
    ![gh-example2]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/github/gh-cli2.png)

- #####  Create a pull request
    Create a **branch**, make several commits to fix the bug described in the issue, and use `gh` to create a *pull request* to share your contribution. By using GitHub CLI to create *pull requests*, it also automatically creates a fork when you don’t already have one, and it pushes your branch and creates your *pull request* to get your change merged

    ![gh-example3]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/github/gh-cli3.png)

- #####  View the status of your work
    Get a quick snapshot the next morning of what happened since you created your *pull request*. `gh` shows the review and check **status** of your *pull requests*

    ![gh-example4]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/github/gh-cli4.png)

- #####  Easily check out pull requests
    One of the maintainers reviewed your *pull request* and requested changes. You probably switched branches since then, so use `gh` to checkout the *pull request* branch. We never remember the right commands either! Make the changes, push them, and soon enough the pull request is merged—congratulations!

    ![gh-example5]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/mlogs/github/gh-cli5.png)

####  How to contribute to GitHub CLI

GitHub CLI is an open-source project by GitHub. From [here](http://github.com/cli/cli) you can contribute to this project

Share your experience with GitHub and your feedback about our article on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="commandline" /><category term="linux" /><category term="git" /><category term="developers" /><category term="beta" /><summary type="html">Here is an easier and more seamless way to work with GitHub from the command line — GitHub CLI, currently it is in beta. Millions of developers rely on GitHub for software development to make it more fun and collaborative. The tool gh brings the GitHub experience right to your terminal.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-cli.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-cli.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Deno.js? How this competes with node.js?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/deno-js-altenative-to-node-js/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Deno.js? How this competes with node.js?" /><published>2020-05-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/deno-js-altenative-to-node-js</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/deno-js-altenative-to-node-js/">Deno is the creation of Ryan Dahl, which is a new JavaScript runtime for the backend, but instead of being written in C++, it’s written in Rust, based on the Tokio platform (which provides the asynchronous runtime needed by JavaScript), running on Google’s V8 engine. It is also a new runtime for executing JavaScript and TypeScript outside of the web browser. 


#### Why should we use this?   

Generally we may get a doubt, why should I use it, here are some of it's features. They are:

##### 1. Security is integrated

Node.js allows you to access read and write into the filesystem, access environment variables, make outgoing requests, etc. As well as it also opens up a security risk if you are not careful when writing code.

So instead, Deno uses command-line arguments to enable or disable access to different security features. So if you need your script to be able to access the /etc folder, you can do:
 
```sh
deno --allow-read=/etc myscript.ts
```
It will allow your code to read from the folder, anything else and you’ll get a security exception. This is similar to how other platforms handle security. 

##### 2. Complete standard library

Deno claims to have a complete standard library allowing developers to use official tools to perform basic tasks and only requiring the use of external libraries for complex tasks and it comes with the tools to add color to terminal text, generate UUIDs, work with external data structures,  and for writing WebSockets.

##### 3. Integrated Typescript

In Deno, by default the integration into JavaScript is done internally, so no need for external tooling. By default Deno takes care of a lot, you can overwrite the configuration by using your own tsconfig.json file:

```sh
deno run -c tsconfig.json [your-script.ts]
```
The default configuration of Deno is to use strict mode, so any ill-advised coding practice will be alerted immediately.


#### Deno Installation

Deno ships as a single executable with no dependencies. You can install it using the installers below: 

##### Using Shell (macOS, Linux):
```sh
$ curl -fsSL https://deno.land/x/install/install.sh | sh
```
##### Using PowerShell (Windows):
```sh
$ iwr https://deno.land/x/install/install.ps1 -useb | iex
```
##### Using Cargo (Windows, macOS, Linux):
```sh
$ cargo install deno
```
##### Using Homebrew (macOS):
```sh
$ brew install deno
```
##### Using Chocolatey (Windows):
```sh
$ choco install deno
```
##### Using Scoop (Windows):
```sh
$ scoop install deno
```


#### Where to learn Deno?

https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-deno-handbook/

#### About author:
Akash rao Mallareddy - `Web Developer, StartUp Enthusiastic, Leader`              
Follow him on [Linkedin](https://www.linkedin.com/in/akash-rao-mallareddy-055520168/), [Github](https://github.com/Akashmallareddy), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/AkashMallareddy)</content><author><name>contributor</name></author><category term="js" /><category term="javascript" /><category term="alternatives" /><summary type="html">Deno is the creation of Ryan Dahl, which is a new JavaScript runtime for the backend, but instead of being written in C++, it’s written in Rust, based on the Tokio platform (which provides the asynchronous runtime needed by JavaScript), running on Google’s V8 engine. It is also a new runtime for executing JavaScript and TypeScript outside of the web browser.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/js/Deno.js.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/js/Deno.js.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsoft Teams vs Slack:The Battle of collaborative work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/microsoft-teams-vs-slack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsoft Teams vs Slack:The Battle of collaborative work" /><published>2020-05-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/microsoft-teams-vs-slack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/microsoft-teams-vs-slack/">Both Microsoft Teams and Slack are collaboration platform tools that combines persistent workplace chat, video meetings, file storage (including collaboration on files), and application integration.   

Back then, Slack began as an internal tool for Stewart Butterfield's company Tiny Speck during the development of Glitch, an online game. Then Slack was launched in August 2013.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/slack-intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; title=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;   

In 2016, Satya Nadella and Bill Gates met up to discuss an important matter. They wanted to bid 8 billion USD to acquire Slack, the SaaS giant that dominated the team chat app space. The meeting had a surprising conclusion: instead of buying Slack, they decided to build their own team chat app tool. In November 2016, Microsoft Teams was officially launched.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/teams-intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Teams&quot; title=&quot;Microsoft Teams&quot; /&gt;  

And now, both Teams and Slack had gained a good amount of daily active users.  

#### Choosing between Slack and Microsoft Teams for your next collaboration tool? Here’s what you need to know about the differences between the two, so you can choose the platform that best suits the needs of your team.  

Talking about features, there is a large difference in both of then. They're  

{:class=&quot;table table-bordered dark&quot;}
|                         |  Slack                                                                                                    |  Microsoft Teams                                                                                                                                                     |
|-------------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| Pricing model           | Freemium Standard $6.67 user/month (billed annually)  Plus $12.50 user/month (billed annually)            | Freemium Office 365 Business Essentials  $5 per user/month(billed annually) $12.50 per user/month(billed annually)  You can try both paid plans for free for 30 days |
| Message history limit   | 10K messages in Free plan, unlimited in Standard and Plus plans                                           | Unlimited in all plans                                                                                                                                               |
| Audio/video calls       | Unlimited 1:1 voice and video calls in Free plan Conference calls for up to 15 participants in Paid plans | Voice/video calls with up to 250 people in a meeting.                                                                                                                |
| Integrations            | 10 integrations limit in Free plan, 800+ integrations in paid plans                                       | 180+ apps and services (as of July 2018)                                                                                                                             |
| File storage limit      | Free plan: 5GB file storage for a team Standard plan: 10GB per user  Plus plan: 20GB per user             | Free plan: 2 GB/user and 10GB of shared storage Paid plans: 1 TB per organization                                                                                    |
| Screen sharing          | Unavailable in Free version, available in Standard and Plus versions                                      | Available in all plans                                                                                                                                               |
| Interface color options | Custom sidebar themes.                                                                                    | 3 themes (light, dark, high contrast)                                                                                                                                |
| Conversation threads    |  Yes                                                                                                      | Yes                                                                                                                                                                  |

### Microsoft Teams integrations vs Slack integrations  

 Microsoft Teams and Slack take slightly different approaches to integration with other apps.  

#### Slack integrations  
Slack boasts a ton of integrations with a variety of different apps—more than 800 for paid plans, to be exact.  
&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/slack-integrations.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack Integrations&quot; title=&quot;Slack Integrations&quot; /&gt;   
The sheer number and variety of apps available means that you can customize your Slack workspace to make your workflow seamless.  

#### Microsoft Teams integrations  

While Slack offers more options for customization, Microsoft Teams takes a different approach—offering a full-fledged collaboration platform with many different functionalities built in from day one.  

Essentially, Teams isn't meant to be a standalone tool. It's a fully integrated Office 365 collaboration hub, allowing users to move seamlessly between tasks and apps within the Teams window.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/teams-integrations.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teams Integrations&quot; title=&quot;Teams Integrations&quot; /&gt;   


### Wrapping up  

Here are some of our conclusions regarding Slack vs. Microsoft Teams.  

**Pricing:** Both Teams and Slack have freemium plans. When it comes to the paid plans, the cheapest Microsoft Teams plan is less expensive than Slack’s cheapest plan. MT wins this roound.  

**Layout and design:** The layout in Microsoft Teams has far too many tabs. On the other hand, there is less to see immediately in Slack because they want to improve their user interface. Moreover, Slack has more options to customize the app’s look.  

**Messaging:** Both Teams and Slack have different ways to send and receive messages, including threads. Microsoft Teams has more built-in options to format your text, and in return, Slack lets you set reminders for individual messages.  

**File sharing and collaboration:** Microsoft Teams lets you share Office files and work on them immediately from the workspace. Slack doesn’t come with the option of editing documents from the workspace, so you have to download files and open them in specific apps to edit them.  

**Video calls:** Both apps allow video calls and the feature works very well. However, Teams has a built-in video recording feature, which is really neat. Moreover, MT allows up to 250 people in a single call when you’re on a paid plan, compared to Slack which allows 15 people at a time.  

**Integrations:** While Microsoft Teams has excellent native integrations with Office and some third-party app integrations, Slack definitely wins in this department – it has more than 800 integrations that you can use.  

**Summary:** Both apps are a good choice but they are catered for different needs. If you want lots of third-party integrations and the ability to customize your app to a great extent go with **Slack**.

On the other hand, **Microsoft Teams** works really well for companies that do a lot of work Office 365 and who already pay for that service.  

If you are planning to use free version, then Microsoft Teams would suit you the best because, there are are a lot more features in Microsoft Teams than Slack. May be this is the reason why, Microsoft Teams had a larger user base.</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="microsoft teams" /><category term="communication" /><category term="trends" /><category term="comparsion" /><summary type="html">Both Microsoft Teams and Slack are collaboration platform tools that combines persistent workplace chat, video meetings, file storage (including collaboration on files), and application integration.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/internet/slack-vs-teams.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/internet/slack-vs-teams.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 cool Linux apps</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/5-cool-linux-apps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 cool Linux apps" /><published>2020-05-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/5-cool-linux-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/5-cool-linux-apps/">In the recent days many people are tending towards linux use. So here are some of the cool apps which you can use.

**1. KDE Connect**:
KDE Connect allow all your devices to communicate with each other.
Here are some of the things that it can do
+ Receive your phone notifications on your desktop computer and reply to messages.
+ Control music playing on your desktop from your phone.
+ Use your phone as a remote control for your desktop.
+ Run predefined commands on your PC from connected devices.
+ Check your phones battery level from the desktop.
+ Ring your phone to help finding it.
+ Share files and links between devices.
+ Browse your phone from the desktop.
+ Control the desktop's volume from the phone.

It is similar to controlling your phone in Windows, but with a lot more features.

You can download it from the official site [here](https://kdeconnect.kde.org/download.html)

**2. Ulauncher**:
It is an application launcher for linux.

It is a great tool where in
+ You can search your apps, files in your system.
+ You can set custom color themes.
+ You can add shortcuts &amp; extensions.
+ Fast directory browser.
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;55%&quot; alt=&quot;Ulanucher&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/linux/ulauncher-theme.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;65%&quot; alt=&quot;Ulanucher&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/linux/ulauncher-search.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
You can accesses it with a shorcut key can create a shortcut for web search or your scripts or install a 3rd party extension. It is a very cool tool..

**3. Wine**:
Wine is a compatibility layer capable of running Windows applications on linux systems.
Simply you can run windows applications on your linux system.

You can download the Wine [here](https://wiki.winehq.org/Download). You can also download it from the software center in linux systems.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;MS office&quot; title=&quot;MS office&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/linux/wine-office.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Matlab&quot; title=&quot;Matlab&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/linux/wine-matlab.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Adobe Photoshop&quot; title=&quot;Adobe Photoshop&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/linux/wine-photoshopcc2015.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
 
**4. AutomaThemely**:
&gt;Simple, set-and-forget python application for changing between desktop themes according to light and dark hours.

It is the application caption.

With this application we can change the desktop themes to light and dark by setting time.

This is there [Github page](https://github.com/C2N14/AutomaThemely). You can download it from [here](https://github.com/C2N14/AutomaThemely/releases)

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;75%&quot; src=&quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/linux/AutomaThemely.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

**5. Gnirehtet**:
Gnirehtet provides reverse tethering for your Android phone.

It allows devices to use the internet connection of the computer they are plugged on. It does not require any root access (neither on the device nor on the computer). It works on Linux,Windows and Mac OS.

You can download it from it's [here](https://github.com/Genymobile/gnirehtet).</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="ubuntu" /><category term="os" /><category term="apps" /><summary type="html">In the recent days many people are tending towards linux use. So here are some of the cool apps which you can use.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/5-cool-linux-apps.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/5-cool-linux-apps.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Github announced the MLH Fellowship for students</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/github-mlh-fellowship-for-students/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Github announced the MLH Fellowship for students" /><published>2020-05-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/github-mlh-fellowship-for-students</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/github-mlh-fellowship-for-students/">These days companies everywhere find themselves quickly changing how they work. With the culture shift that comes along with remote work, it’s fair to say that collaboration is already starting to be different.

[GitHub Education](https://education.github.com/), always helps the next generation of developers to make their best in work. Now, more than ever, students need opportunities to sustain their growth. Github together with their partners **Major League Hacking (MLH)**, solving this problem with a new program—the **MLH Fellowship**, Powered by **GitHub**. This remote program matches up *pods* of 8-10 students with **open-source projects and mentors** over a period of 12 weeks. Students will receive a stipend for the program through **GitHub Sponsors**.

![github-quote](https://i0.wp.com/user-images.githubusercontent.com/1874003/80812907-e87bbc80-8b96-11ea-914b-8a35398996a4.jpg?ssl=1)

Not just GitHub, many other tech companies will come together and fuel this ecosystem. To kick off the program, GitHub Education plans to support **100 MLH Fellows** in the inaugural class of summer 2020. These are the other partners who're joining this coalition Facebook, DEV, and the Royal Bank of Canada.

This is how GitHub describes about MLH Fellowship

##### GitHub's vision: Workforce innovation to meet student demand

Enterprises want to stay competitive with recent graduates, and internship programs often provide that edge. Internships also serve as a credential: For future hiring managers, an internship with a top tech company is a good indication of a quality candidate.

But for students, many, many more of them apply for those coveted roles than there are positions to fill. For most students, a summer in Silicon Valley is often out of the question for those aspiring developers, maintainers, and engineering managers. In partnering with MLH, we’re looking to welcome a new global workforce that is trained in real-world workflows and collaboration

CEO of MLH, Mike Swift, points to the program’s design around remote work and public projects:

&gt; Enabling students to spend their summer contributing to the software that runs the world is a unique     opportunity for them. They’ll work on meaningful projects with their peers under the guidance of some of the world’s most talented engineers. The remote nature of this program will democratize access to internships for countless students worldwide.

###### The opportunity: Shape the future of work
In this moment, companies have the opportunity to affect how we learn, collaborate, and share for decades to come. We hope to see the results of these particular efforts in as little as 12 months when this year’s group of interns graduate.

&gt; Let’s keep education moving forward. Students, we got you. - GitHub


#### Read to level-up your learning?

Apply to GitHub MLH Fellowship and join them  from [here](http://fellowship.mlh.io/)

Share your experience with GitHub Fellowship and your feedback about our article on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="fellowship" /><category term="internship" /><category term="mlh-fellowship" /><category term="github-education" /><summary type="html">These days companies everywhere find themselves quickly changing how they work. With the culture shift that comes along with remote work, it’s fair to say that collaboration is already starting to be different.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-mlh.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/mlogs/github/github-mlh.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compare-dell-xps-15-and-xps-17/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15" /><published>2020-05-19T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compare-dell-xps-15-and-xps-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compare-dell-xps-15-and-xps-17/">Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15

The company has made big changes to its XPS lineup, with the much-rumored redesign of the XPS 15 and a new XPS 17.
What do these laptops bring to the market let's find in this article?

![]({{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17.jpeg)

Lets first talk about the XPS 15, The new XPS 15 design has seen a significant redesign after nearly 5 years and it now comes with a bigger 16:10 aspect ratio and trimmed down bezels, similar to that of Dell XPS 13.
You can either pick a 4k or a regular FHD (1920 x 1200) display with a small webcam on top for Windows 10 Hello Facial Recognition. It also offers a fingerprint for authentication.

![]({{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-display.jpeg)

+ Powering this is the new 10th gen mobile processors from Intel which can be equipped up to a Core i9 and it also comes with an option for dedicated graphics namely the  Nvidia’s GeForce GTX 1650 Ti Max-Q for graphically intense task.

+ This laptop ditches ports like USB-A and HDMI in favor of USB-C and this laptop comes with two USB-C with Thunderbolt 3 support and a regular USB-C 3.1 port, and full-size SD card reader. This laptop is quite thinner at 18mm high.

![]({{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-ports.jpg)

+ Talking about battery, Dell is promising “The longest battery life of any 15-inch laptop”, with up to 25 hours on the FHD display model and It also comes with Quad speaker setup(2 front facing and 2 at rear) for immersive sound experience. 

This laptop starts at **$1,299.99**.

Alongside the XPS 15, Dell reintroduced it's slightly bigger XPS 17. It’s been nearly 10 years since we have seen an XPS 17 and as the name implies it's a larger 17-inch laptop and dell claims that “The XPS 17 is the smallest 17-inch laptop on the planet”. 
Similar to the XPS 15 this laptop also comes with a 16:10 aspect ratio and a much smaller bezel.

![]({{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-17.jpeg)

This 17-inch laptop also comes new 10th gen intel processors, which can be equipped up to the new core i9 and at the GPU side of things, this can be equipped with either Nvidia’s GTX 1650 Ti Max-Q or the more powerful RTX 2060. With this CPU and GPU combination Dell claims this laptop to be the &quot;Most powerful XPS laptop ever&quot;.

+ Talking about the ports, this comes with four USB-C Thunderbolt 3 ports and a full-size SD card reader and the fact that it does not have any USB-A port is a bummer. 
+ Dell has added a new thermal design to the XPS 17 with a custom vapor chamber, to improve airflow and sustain high performance for longer periods of time.
+ It also comes with Quad speaker setup(2 front facing and 2 at rear) for immersive sound experience.

![]({{site.baseurl}}/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-speakers.jpeg)

The new Dell XPS 17 will be available soon starting at **$1,499.99**.</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="dell" /><category term="computers" /><category term="versions" /><category term="comparsions" /><summary type="html">Dell launches new XPS 17 and redesigned XPS 15</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-2020-feature-image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/dell/dell-xps-15-17-2020-feature-image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google’s FooBar - The Secret Hiring Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-foobar-challenge-invitation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google's FooBar - The Secret Hiring Challenge" /><published>2020-05-18T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-foobar-challenge-invitation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-foobar-challenge-invitation/">Did you got Google’s Foobar Invitation. First of all, **congratulations**, you should know that, this is not an ordinary invitation,, As  Google sends this hiring invitation to only some special developers.

&gt; If you haven't got this invitation this blog will help you to understand who are eligible and to be prepared for the next hiring challenge.

**FooBar** is weird term used by Google for it's secret hiring challenge.

##### What is FooBar?
[Google Foobar](https://foobar.withgoogle.com/) is Google’s secret hiring challenge. Google uses this to hire some of the best developers around the globe which they think can be a good match for their organization. Many developers in Google have been hired through this hiring challenge.

##### How can I get the invitation:
Getting the invitation for [Google Foobar](https://foobar.withgoogle.com/) is also a mysterious thing, no one exactly knows the criteria for the Google Foobar invitation eligibility. 
As per the known information

Google send the invitation on the basis of your **search history** and **your problem solving related keyword searches**, like if you are a developer, it is obvious that you search a lot of problems related to programming on Google or Stack Overflow. And based on Google search algorithms, they show you an invitation for [Google Foobar](https://foobar.withgoogle.com/).

This is how the invitation looks like - 

&gt; “You’re speaking our language. Up for a challenge?”

![foobar-invitation]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/google/foobar-invitation.jpg)

##### How can I take this challenge without an invitation?

We appreciate your interest towards this but, the sad thing is without an invitation from Google, you can't enter into this hiring challenge

As we already said that Google Foobar is an invitation based hiring challenge. That means, you can only take the challenge if you have got the invitation from Google for Foobar.

![foobar-without-invitation]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/google/foobar-without-invitation.jpg)

##### What happens after getting an invitation?

When you get the invitation, and you accepted that, you will be redirected to [Google's Foobar](https://foobar.withgoogle.com/) website which looks like a linux command-line interface. 
![foobar-interface]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/google/foobar-home.jpg)

After you request for the challenge using the command `request`, you will get some files in your Foobar command-line folder which contains some competitive programming question waiting for you.You can submit your answers either in **Java** or **Python**.
You will get two files to write the solution to your problem statement `solution.java` and `solution.py`. You can write your solution in your preferred language out of these two.


You can `save` and `run` the files and once you're confident you can `submit` and  `verify` the results.

![foobar-coding]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/google/foobar-coding.jpg) 

In a similar way you'll have **five** levels to complete.


![foobar-levels]({{ site.baseurl}}/assets/images/google/foobar-levels.jpg)

After you complete all the 5 levels, you get a form to fill your name and your contact details to contact you.

Once you clear your interview you'll be offered a Software Developer role at Google depending on your interests, Skills and performance in interviews.

&gt; All the  best for your Google's FooBar challenge


Note: All the images that helped you to understand better are taken from different sources like  - Google, Medium, Quora. Our  Thanks to all of the above sites.

Share your experience with Google's Foobar and your feedback on [twitter](https://twitter.com/devskrate), [Instagram](https://instagram.com/devskrate), or mail us at [support@devskrate.com](mailto:support@devskrate.com). Use [#DevsKrate](https://devskrate.com) on any social media platforms we will reach out to you.</content><author><name>satya</name></author><category term="developerstuff" /><category term="jobs" /><category term="students" /><category term="internship" /><summary type="html">Did you got Google’s Foobar Invitation. First of all, congratulations, you should know that, this is not an ordinary invitation,, As Google sends this hiring invitation to only some special developers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/google-foobar.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/google-foobar.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Microsoft Student Partner?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-is-microsoft-student-partner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Microsoft Student Partner?" /><published>2020-05-17T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/what-is-microsoft-student-partner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-is-microsoft-student-partner/">There are many organizations that run student ambassador programs for students going through colleges and universities. One among those, but the most reputed program is offered by Microsoft named as &lt;a href=&quot;https://studentambassadors.microsoft.com/en-us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program&lt;/a&gt;, formaly Microsoft Student Partner Program.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/student-partner-intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot;&gt;

### What is Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador

The Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors program is a global group of on-campus ambassadors who are eager to help students and their communities, lead in their local tech circles, and develop technical and career skills for the future. As a Student Ambassador, you might find yourself organizing a campus or community hackathon, mentoring other students.

Microsoft quoted the program as.....

&gt; Looking for student leaders with a passion for making a difference, building vibrant communities, and sharing the latest tech with their peers.

### When did it all started?

The MSP Program was initiated back in **2001**, and operated in **15 countries** for five years. In late **2006**, the program was expanded to **50 countries** worldwide, and as of July 2010, there are more than **2800 members** worldwide across 101 countries and regions.

### Transformation from Student Partner to Learn Student Ambassador

On July 1, the current Microsoft Student Partner program will evolve to become the Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors program. All active members of the program will be invited to become Student Ambassadors and the first cohort will be announced in early July.

### Eligibility

To apply, you must be at least 16 years old, have valid identification and be actively enrolled in an accredited, higher education academic institution.

Students from all academic backgrounds who want to grow their career and tech skills while making a difference in their communities to apply. Some experience in coding or technology is helpful, but we have tools and resources to help you learn in the program.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/student-partner-works.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador&quot;&gt;

### Benefits

As it turns out, earning these benefits involves doing some pretty fun things. We have four milestones for our Student Ambassadors:

- Alpha 1 - Jump on board and get active in the Teams community.
- Alpha 2 - Complete a Microsoft Learn path and unlock Azure credits with Visual Studio Enterprise subscription benefits.
- Beta - Host an event in your community to unlock event support and resource benefits. This effort could include an invitation to join our annual Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors Summit.
- Gold - Get invited to the Gold milestone when you’ve gone above and beyond in earning your badges and serving your local community. You’ll become a Student Ambassadors Regional Leader, gain access to special events, and may be invited to become a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP).

### Resources that can be accessed by Student Ambassadors

These benefits include but aren’t limited to:

- Access to Office 365, plus Snagit and Camtasia screen capture and recording software.
- Visual Studio Enterprise subscription and \$150 monthly Azure credits.
- Event support.
- Engagement with Cloud Advocates and Microsoft MVPs.
- Student Ambassador Milestone badges to highlight program accomplishments on your LinkedIn profile.

### Application Process:

**Step 1:**To apply to the Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://studentambassadors.microsoft.com/en-us/Form&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://studentambassadors.microsoft.com/en-us/Form&lt;/a&gt;.

**Step-2:**Read tha Application Notification to know when does your application gets reviewed.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot;&gt;

**Step-3:**Then fill out all your Personal Info like first name, last name, contact email, gender, and phone number, and then verify the phone number through an OTP.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot;&gt;

**Step-:4**In this step fill all our College Details.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot;&gt;

**Step-5:**In this step, there are a few questions that test your view on technology and leadership.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot;&gt;

**Step-7:**Here you have to fill all your URLs of profiles and other info.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot;&gt;

**Step-8:**In the last step, check all your Technical Skills.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/microsoft/msp-apply-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot; title=&quot;Student Learn Ambassador Application&quot;&gt;

And, then submit your application for the Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program. Hope this post will help you find your path to successful Microsoft Student Ambassader Program and wish you a very good luck.</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="microsoft" /><category term="student partner" /><category term="ambassador" /><summary type="html">There are many organizations that run student ambassador programs for students going through colleges and universities. One among those, but the most reputed program is offered by Microsoft named as Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador program, formaly Microsoft Student Partner Program.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/msp-featured-image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/msp-featured-image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cool websites to visit, when you get bored!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/websites-to-visit-when-bored/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cool websites to visit, when you get bored!" /><published>2020-05-16T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/websites-to-visit-when-bored</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/websites-to-visit-when-bored/">Have you ever felt bored? Ofcourse YES... I know. Here are the cool websites to visit when you feel bored on internet.  
#### 1. FREESOUND  
FreeSound is the largest database of sound tracks that are available for free and when I say largest, I mean it.. So, There are tons of paid sites, that sell sound tracks. But if you ever need one, then go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://freesound.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;freesound.org&lt;/a&gt;. You can find anything for a Bleep sound to a audio of someone flushing a toilet.

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/freesound.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FreeSound&quot; title=&quot;FreeSound&quot;&gt;

#### 2. NAPFLIX  
Unlike Netflix, which keep you awake at nights. &lt;a href=&quot;http://napflix.tv/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Napflix&lt;/a&gt; will help you fall asleep. It shows you hours of boring videos, which will calm you down And probably help you to sleep faster.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/napflix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NapFlix&quot; title=&quot;NapFlix&quot;&gt;

#### 3. webkay - What every Browser knows about you  
This website tells you what your browser know about you, and all the website can access these data without asking your permission. Like your approx Location, your OS and the browser, what computer are you using, what social media are you logged in and a lot of other private stuff.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/webkay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;webkay&quot; title=&quot;webkay&quot;&gt;

But what I really want to point out here is that The online sites also track your battery percentage not just in desktop, but also on mobile. So, imagine, you want to book an uber with less than 5% battery juice. Well, then then technically, it’s possible for the company to increase price just for you. Not saying this would happen, but technically it’s possible.  

Visit webkay &lt;a href=&quot;http://webkay.robinlinus.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;

#### 4. Super Log Out  
Well, talking about the browser, try out super log. It’s a simple app that automatically log you out of all the sign in account on your browser with just one click.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/superlogout.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Super Log Out&quot; title=&quot;Super Log Out&quot;&gt;

When you are using a public or friends computer though, don’t click on the link Unless you really want to use this service.  

Visit Super Log Out &lt;a href=&quot;http://superlogout.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;color:red; background-color:#D3D3D3;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;Caution: Dont Visit, unless you require it!!!&lt;/span&gt;  
#### 5. Button Bass  
This website plays a EDM loop when you tap a cube and if you are good with this, you can make your own music.  

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/buttonbass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Button Bass&quot; title=&quot;Button Bass&quot;&gt;

And that’s not all, There are several other genre like dubstep, electronic and yes, there are android apps for that as well. Though, there is no option to record the audio. So, you’ll have to use sound sought of workaround.   

Visit Button Bass &lt;a href=&quot;http://buttonbass.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;    


#### 6. Radio Garden  
Now, let me tell you a secret, back then in 1980, we used to have a big radio in our house. It’s quite wonderful, how quickly technology change. So, anyways, Radio garden is music website that let you listen to 8000 live radio station from all around the world. It’s a great way to discover new songs from different language.  
Visit Radio Garden &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.garden/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/images/internet/radiogarden.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Radio Garden&quot; title=&quot;Radio Garden&quot;&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="internet" /><category term="bored tech" /><summary type="html">Have you ever felt bored? Ofcourse YES… I know. Here are the cool websites to visit when you feel bored on internet. 1. FREESOUND FreeSound is the largest database of sound tracks that are available for free and when I say largest, I mean it.. So, There are tons of paid sites, that sell sound tracks. But if you ever need one, then go to freesound.org. You can find anything for a Bleep sound to a audio of someone flushing a toilet.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/internet/bored-internet.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/internet/bored-internet.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>